片名《叫我第一名》
Front of the class
我叫布莱德·科恩
My name is Bradley Cohen.
但我的小时候，人们还叫我很多别的“名字”
But when l was a kid, people called me by lots of names.
我弟弟杰夫叫我“波波医生”
My brother, Jeff, called me Dr. Bobo.
我妈叫我“宝贝”
My mom called me honey.
学校的同学呢
And the kids at school?
叫什么的都有：“神经病”、“怪胎”等等
Well, they called me everything from spaz to freak.
我没什么朋友
I didn't have many friends actually.
但却有个形影不离的伙伴一直陪着我
But I did have a constant companion.
自从他来了后，我就想不起他有不在我身边的时候
I can barely remember a time, when it wasn't there.
有时他不会给我带来麻烦
Now sometimes, it wasn't a problem for me.
有时，就会
Other times, it was.
丢掉什么？丢掉书？
Drop what? Drop books?
住手！
Stop it.
- 你紧张吗，布莱德？你有什么毛病吗？
Are you scared Brad? What's wrong?
- 少来烦我
Leave me alone.
打! 打! 打!
Fight! Fight! Fight!
- 你们在干嘛！
What is going on!
- 来啊，有种就来打！   - 住手！
-Com'on. Bring it on!  - Stop.
不许再打了！住手！都回去上课！
Stop that fighting right now! Stop! Get back to class!
别胡闹了，你的麻烦大啦！
Stop that nonsense. You are in big trouble, mister.
“女孩掉进泥巴里弄脏了”
The girl fell in the mud and got dirty.
我和我忠诚的伙伴有个共识，那就是我们都讨厌学校
One thing my Constant Companion and, I agreed on was that we hated school.
我等不及想走掉
I couldn't wait until I got out.
不用再写作业，不用再看书，不用再看老师难看的脸色
No more homework, no more books, no more teachers' dirty looks.
我的伙伴是在我6岁时出现的
My Companion first showed up, when I was six
但是过了很多年，他才有了个名字
but it was years before it had a name.
但在眼下，精神科医生说我只是亢奋多动
Now the shrinks said I was just hyper;
我会发出怪声和做怪动作，来让自己吸引到注意
I made funny noises and acted, weird to draw attention to myself.
这只是一个过渡期，我长大以后就会恢复正常
It was just a phase: I'd grow out of it and be "normal"....
跟别人一样
...like everybody else.
一直以来，这个伴儿一直跟着我
Through it all, my constant companion stuck with me.
现在我的朋友只是觉得，我本来就是这样
Now, to my friends, I'm just regular, ole Brad.
“老布莱德”——喜欢棒球，爱听80年代的老歌
The guy who likes baseball. And who loves cheesy 80's music.
他们觉得这比我发出的怪声更怪
Which they think is much weirder, than the noises I make.
下午好警官，我超速了吗？
Afternoon, officer. Was I speeding?
超过速限12哩
Twelve miles over the limit.
圣路易？你是观光客？
St. Louis, huh? You a tourist?
不，我住在亚特兰大，刚搬来这里
No, I live in Atlanta now, I just moved here.
我刚才大概有点分心吧
I guess I was a little distracted...
小子，你喝酒了？
Son, you been drinking...?
不，不，警官。我有“图雷特氏综合症”
No. No, sir.I have Tourette Syndrome.
别紧张，请你在这里签名
Take it easy, son. I'm going to need you to sign this.
你要找什么样的工作？
So. What kind of job you looking for?
教书
Teaching.
我想当老师
I'm going to be a teacher.
我经常看到这种表情
I get that look a lot;
但我从来不放在心上
but I never let it get to me.
你有布莱德利大学的学士学位
I see you've got a B.A. from Bradley University -
- 那是在伊利诺依州吧？
that's in Illinois, isn't it?
- 是的
Yes, ma'am !
毕业成绩优异，推荐度很高
Graduated cum laude, high recommendations,
你的教学成果评估非常优异，好极了
your student teaching evals are outstanding, excellent.
你怎么会决定要教书？
What made you decide to go into teaching?
我一直都在想教书，我觉得我天生是老师的料
It's all I've ever wanted to do. I feel like I was born to teach.
为什么选择来亚特兰大？
Why choose Atlanta?
我是说…你的家乡在密苏里州
I mean...Missouri's your home.
我想当勇士队的球迷，所以……
I'm thinking of becoming a Braves fan.So, ahh...
乔治亚州承认我的伊利诺伊州的教学执照
Georgia honors my Illinois teaching certificate.
而且，我来这里当营队辅导员时
Plus I fell in love with Atlanta
我喜欢上了亚特兰大
when I worked down here as a camp counselor.
现在我就住这里
I live here now.
我父亲和我继母也住这里
So does my Dad and my Stepmom.
很高兴你能得到家人的支持
Well, it's nice to have family here to...give you support.
我们还是来谈谈“大象”吧
Maybe we should talk about the elephant.
大象？
Elephant?
这屋子里的“大象”，我的图雷特氏症
In the room: my Tourette's.
不行，根据美国残障保护法案，我不能问你…
No. The Americans with Disabilities Act doesn't allow me to ask you...
我知道，但我想告诉你，就像我想告诉我的学生一样
I know, but I'd like to tell you  - just like I tell the kids in my classes.
我跟他们解释这是大脑方面的问题
See, I explain to them that it's a brain thing
导致让我发出奇怪的声音——就像打喷嚏一样控制不了
that causes me to make strange noises --they're like sneezes, irrepressible.
你想打喷嚏就非打不可
When you have to,
非打不可
you have to.
学生都有什么回应？
How do they react?
他们明白以后就接受了
Once they understand, they're fine with it.
在课堂上这些从来不是问题
It's never caused any problems in a classroom.
我只想得到一个机会
All I want is a chance.
能去面试的机会
Just get me the interviews,
向他们证明我能胜任这个工作
and let me prove to them that I can do the job.
美国残障保护法案明文规定，我有权利得到这样的机会
The Americans with Disabilities Act says I'm entitled to a chance.
罗恩！
Ron!
嘿，情况怎么样？
Hey, how'd it go?
他们说：谁想要像狗叫的老师
Oh, you know: "Who wants a teacher that barks like a dog?
叫我去找其他行当的工作
You should try another line of work."
真的吗？
Are you serious?
他们没看你的履历？
Didn't they look at your resume?
你在开我玩笑啦
You're kidding.
他们会安排我跟几位校长面试
They're setting up interviews with some principals.
太棒了，什么时候？
- Fantastic! - When?
我不知道，我要等他们的电话
Oh, I don't know. I've gotta wait for their calls.
换衣服，我们去庆祝一下
Get changed - we gotta go celebrate.
你不是有约会吗？
Haven't you got a date?
我看她能不能带个朋友一起来
I'll see if she's got a friend.
你也该认识几个女生了
It's about time you started meeting some chicks.
我现在没心情交女朋友
I can't focus on dating right now.
有没有人说过你顽固透顶？
Has anybody ever tell you you're obsessive?
每个我去看过的精神科医生都这么说
Only every shrink I ever saw.
那你保持这可笑的专注吧
Well, have fun focusing.
你爸又打电话来了
Oh -- your Dad called again.
你有空还是给他回个电话吧
Maybe you should call him back,you know?
好，回见
All right. I'll see you later.
给我爸回电话？
Returning Dad's call?
那我得作好准备才行
I'd have to prepare for that.
爸和妈在我很小的时候就离婚了
See, Mom and Dad had divorced when I was a little kid and my relationship
我和我爸的关系一直都……怎么说？挺复杂吧
with Dad had always been - umm, let's just say -- complicated?
我磨光了他的耐性，就像黑板上的钉子一样
I mean, I wore out his patience like nails on a chalkboard.
更糟的是我弟弟杰夫也有点多动
It didn't help that my brother Jeff was also a little hyper.
- 爸爸说他要赶着回亚特兰大的家
Dad said he's waiting to get back to his home in Atlanta,
他想跟你说再见
he's waiting to say goodbye -
再见！
Goodbye!
你会惹他生气啦
You're gonna make him mad!
来，我们比赛！
Come on -- I'll race you!
想跟我比？门儿都没有
Against The Green Dragon? You gotta be kidding --
- 笨蛋！
Sucker!
- 你作弊！
Cheater!
抄捷径！
Short cut!
你骑脚踏车耶！
You got a bike.
再见了，杰夫
See you, Jeff.
不公平啦
Hey! That's not fair!
- 来啊！
Aw, com'on!
- 杰夫
Jeff!
你赢不了我啦
You're not going to beat me!
看，我就要赢了
See, I'm gonna win.
不公平！你骑脚踏车！
That's not fair! You got a bike!
不准你这样！不！你作弊！
Oh, no you're not! Oh, no! You are!
你这家伙！小声点啦
Hey guys! quiet down, you guys, quiet down.
别吵到邻居了 - 过来
We do have neighbors you know. Come here.
- 看吧，我赢了
See, I did beat you.
冷静下来。布莱德，过来亲爱的，请你专心一点好吗？
Yeah. Calm down. Brad, com'ere. Com'on honey, focus, would you?
过来，过来这里，站好了
Com'ere. Come here! Stand here.
听着，听我说，请你专心好吗？
Listen. Listen up. Focus, please. All right?
请你们帮我一个忙
I need you guys to do me a favor.
你们俩要多体谅妈妈，OK？
I want you both to make life a little easier for your mom, okay?
你们快把她搞疯了…听好！住手！布莱德！
You are driving her nuts. Guys, listen! Hey, hey. Stop it! Brad!
要帮忙她做家务事
Help her out around the house;
但首先，不能再有这些烦人的举动了，好吗？
but most of all let us stop the obnoxious behavior, OK? --
嗨，听着，我是认真的！
Hey, listen. I mean it!
别再闹了！
OK? Quit the clowning.
你弟弟觉得好玩，但我不觉得！
Your brother may think its funny, but I don't.
我控制不了嘛
I can't help it.
不，你可以的
Yes, you can.
只要稍微控制一点就行了
There's nothing wrong with you that a little self-control wouldn't fix.
现在，停下！
Now, stop it.
- 诺曼？  - 什么事？
-Norman?  -Yeah!
- 飞机可是不等人的哦
They're not going to hold that plane for you.
- 好，好了，抱一下
Okay, all right. Gimme a hug.
- 爸爸，再见
See you, Dad!
- 再见了，小杰米
Bye-bye, J-man
- 爸，我爱你
I love you, Dad.
- 我也爱你
Love you too, kiddo.
- 听好了，下次去我家住吧，怎么样？
Hey, listen up; we'll stay at my house next time. OK?
- 好，我带你们去看勇士队的球赛
OK! I'll get tickets to a Braves' game.
布莱德，记住刚才我们讲的
And Brad, remember what we talked about:
要自制一点，好吗？
Self-control. All right?
- 妈，需要帮忙吗？
- Need any help with anything, Mom?
- 既然你提到了就来帮忙吧
- Well...now that you mention it....
离婚后，我和杰夫帮忙妈妈创业
After the divorce, Jeff and I helped Mom with her new business.
她在四处兜售精品高级服饰
Sort of a high class traveling boutique.
可能也不算是帮忙啦
Well, maybe helped isn't exactly the right word.
艾伦，这些衣服好漂亮
Oh, Ellen, these things are exquisite!
在圣路易找不到这种流行款式
You never find styles like this in St. Louis.
这是直接从加州来的，比佛利山庄
Well, it is direct from California. Beverly Hills.
大家都这样穿
This is what everyone is wearing.
你看这件。孩子们？孩子们！
Look at this. Boys? Boys!
躲猫猫？
Hide and seek?
- 开始数
Count.
- 1
One...
艾伦，我不想看两位数大码的衣服
Now, Ellen, I don't want to see anything in double-digits.
亲爱的，加州的东西都偏小
Oh, honey, everything in California runs small.
你试穿看看
Go ahead. Just try it on.
布莱德，能请你冷静下来吗？
Brad, would you please calm down?
他像狗一样吠耶！
He's barking like a dog, for goodness sake!
看
Now look.
请别误会
Don't take this the wrong way -
我是把你当朋友才说这些的
you know I wouldn't say this to you if we weren't friends -
你有没有考虑过找人驱魔？
but have you considered an exorcist?
我觉得你还是要面对现实，你的尺寸是12号
You know, I think you might have to face. the fact that you're a size 12.
如果你觉得不好，我帮你剪标
I can cut the label, if it makes you feel better.
这是个新医生，听听他怎么说好吗
It's a new doctor; let's just listen to what he has to say.
我都知道他会说什么了
I know what he'll have to say.
你因为离婚的事生你妈的气吗？布莱德
Do you feel any anger toward your mother,because of the divorce, Brad?
没，没有
No. No.
你因为爸爸不跟你住而生他气吗？
Do you resent your father because he doesn't live with you anymore?
没
No.
爸妈离婚你会自责吗？
Do you blame yourself for the divorce, Brad?
那时我还很小，我甚至都记不清了
It happened when I was a little kid, I don't even remember it.
科恩太太，布莱德无法接受父母离婚
Mrs. Chen, Brad has some serious denial issues regarding the divorce.
需要在家里要给他划定很明确的界限
What he needs at home are some clear boundaries.
要让他明白这样的行为完全无法被接受
He needs to understand that this behavior is totally unacceptable.
而这，就是你的职责了，科恩太太
And that, Mrs. Cohen, is your job.
最难过的就是我让妈妈很辛苦
The hardest part was knowing how tough I made things for Mom.
我在尽量帮她忙了
I tried as best as I could for her.
要记得给他按时吃药
Make sure he keeps taking his medication, OK?
至于我爸？
And for Dad?
三振！
Strike three!
我打棒球
I played sports.
在球场上，我是如鱼得水
On the ball field, I fit right in.
我是说，每个打棒球的人都会发出怪声，做一些奇怪的动作
I mean, everybody makes funny noises and has strange tics at a baseball game.
波波加油！
Go, Bobo!
布莱德加油！快！
Come on, Brad!
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
好了，要点什么？
All right. What can l get you?
听好了，我有好消息要告诉你们
Hey, guys. I got something pretty exciting to tell you.
别吃这么快，你会打嗝的
Honey, don't eat so fast. You're gonna get the hiccups.
- 他老是在打嗝
He's always got the hiccups.
- 你才打嗝咧
You're a hiccup!
听好了，你别这么激动好吗？
Listen, hey! Would you just relax?.
妈妈说你一直都没吃药
Mom says you're not taking your meds.
这样你怎么会…你怎么能冷静下来？
How are you ever...how are you ever going to calm down
如果你都不按医生说的去做
if you don't do what the doctor tells you to do?
吃药只会更严重的啦
Pills just make it worse.
是吗，现在你才是医生吗？
Oh I see. So you're a doctor now, too?
- 他是波波医生
He's Dr. Bobo.
- 闭嘴！
Shut up!
好了，我们吃东西吧
All right, guys, let's eat, guys.
我有重要的消息要宣布，听我说
I have a very important announcement to make.
孩子们？孩子们！好，闹够了，回车上去，走吧
Guys? Guys! All right. That's it. We're going back to the car. Come on.
我还饿呢
I'm still hungry --
你知道我想怎样吗？希望你有一天不要胡闹
You know what would be nice? One day without you acting up.
一天就好了
One.
爸，等等我！
Wait up, Dad.
你要宣布什么事，爸？
So, what's the announcement, Dad?
我有新对象了
I've been seeing someone.
“新对象”是什么意思？
What do you mean seeing somebody?
她叫黛安，她…
Her name is Diane, and she....
布莱德，请你别再这样
Brad, please! Stop doing that!
我没办法
I can't.
我意思是，还没决定什么啦，但...
I mean, nothings' happened yet, but...
你们想不想会有个继母？
how would you guys feel about having a stepmom?
才不！
No way!
我们已经有妈妈了
We've already got a Mom!
现在会有两个啊
Well. Now you're gonna have two.
我跟你妈说了，她不介意，她说…
I talked to your mom about it and she's fine with it. She said...
我叫你别再这样！停下！
I said STOP It! STOP It!
爸爸发脾气我不怪他
See, I really couldn't blame Dad for losing it.
我的怪动作把他搞疯了
My tics drove him nuts.
因为他也跟我的老师一样，不知道我为什么会有奇怪的行为
Because, like my teachers, he had no name for my strange behavior.
只知道这是“无法容忍”的
Except "insufferable".
不知道为什么，我的成绩还可以
Now, somehow -- I don't know how --I made okay grades.
但正常人要做一个小时的事，我需要两个小时
But, what would take a normal person an hour, took me two.
甚至三个小时，我喜欢学习，但我讨厌念书
Or three. I mean, I loved learning, but I hated, hated reading.
我一专心，那个忠诚的伙伴就会捣蛋
Trying to concentrate brought out the worst in my Constant Companion.
布莱德？请你过来
Brad? Come up here, please.
我知道你爱耍宝，但我受够你了
I know you think you're the class clown, but I've had it with you.
我不能…控制…控制不了
I can't - help -help it.
你每次都这样讲，我不想再听什么借口了
That's what you always say. I don't want to hear any more excuses.
同学们想念书…
Your classmates are trying to study...
你这样闹腾会妨碍他们
...and your clowning makes it impossible.
对不起
I'm sorry.
别跟我道歉，你要跟他们道歉
Don't apologize to me. Apologize to them.
各位同学，看这边，请你们坐好
Eyes up here, everyone. Sit up straight, please.
布莱德有话要跟你们说
Brad has something to say to you.
对不起 我……
I'm sorry l...
害得你们没办法念书
that you can't study because of me.
还有呢？
And?
你要保证不再发出怪声了
You promise never to make any more silly noises ever again.
我保证不会再发出怪声
Promise I won't make any more silly noises ever again.
回去坐好，大家继续看书
Take your seat. All of you, back to your books.
这些对你来说也许很艰难
As difficult as this may be for you,
科恩太太，你也许很难接受，但老师们都无计可施了
Mrs. Cohen, I assure you, the teachers are at their wits end.
- 当然我能理解…     - 莎伦，我不接任何电话
-I understand that, of course... - Sharon, would you hold all my calls?
- 但我们只能…
...but all we...
- 这是最后一次机会了，真的是最后一次
Now, this has got to be the last chance. The very last chance.
布莱德，我找你妈妈来
Brad, look, I sent for your mother
因为你在学校的状况很失控
because things have just gotten out of control here.
今天她要带你回家。你可以再来上学…
Now, she's going to take you home today. You can come back...
我控制不了
Can't help it.
对不起，你说什么？
Sorry, what did you say?
他说他控制不了
He said he can't help it.
- 好吧
Right.
- 如果他说的是实话呢？
What if he's telling the truth?
你儿子很聪明，科恩太太，但你再替他找借口…
You've got a bright boy, Mrs. Cohen,but making excuses for him...
替他找借口是帮不了他的
Making excuses is not going to help.
- 他需要在这段时间里问下自己…
Now, he needs to use this time to ask himself ...
- 布莱德，我们走吧
Brad! Com'on. Let's go.
问他自己为何要自毁前程
...this question: "Why am I sabotaging myself?"
就算被退学也无所谓，我讨厌那所学校
I don't care if they expel me. I hate that school.
不管哪一所学校都一样啦
Well, it's that school or another school.
我讨厌所有的学校。我们来这里干嘛？
I hate all schools. Why are we going here -- ?
来找答案
To find some answers.
我不能进图书馆，他们会把我赶出来。求求你
I can't go in the library --they'll throw me out. Please, Mom.
好吧，你过来，坐这儿
All right, com'ere. Sit over here.
- 也许是我们方向错了
Well, maybe we're just going down the wrong track.
- 谁？
Who?
我们大家
All of us.
放开我！
Get off me!
- 吉娃娃…
Wet Willie!
- 极刑！不要极刑啦！
Oh no, wet Willie!
我知道你很忙，诺曼，我不会占用你太多的时间
I know you're busy, Norman, I won't take up much of your time
只是想告诉你…
but I really think you should hear this --
孩子们，小声一点，我在跟爸爸讲话
Boys, keep it down --I'm trying to talk to your Dad!
- 我要跟他讲话
I wanna talk to him!
- 等一下！小声！
In a minute! Keep it down!
听着，那些老师和那个医生
Listen. You know,those teachers and that doctor,
他们都觉得是父母不尽责
to them it's all about bad parenting which, of course,
其实也就是指我，因为我是单亲
comes down to me because I'm the only one who here -
我不是在怪你，诺曼
No. I'm not blaming you, Norman.
其实我是不想再自责了
In fact, I'm going to stop blaming myself.
我跟一位朋友聊过，她认为是医生诊断有误
I was talking to a friend and she think the doctors are missing something.
我去图书馆借了一堆医学书
I got this stack of medical books from the library.
- 妈，小心！    - 我做了些…
-Mom, watch out! -And, I've been doing a little...
研究…
research...
别再说他欠管教了，诺曼！
Stop saying he just needs more discipline, Norman!
我不管做什么都不能让他…
Nothing I do helps -
他控制不了自己，我也无计可施
He is out of control and I'm at the end of my rope -
我可以跟爸爸讲话吗？
Can I talk to Dad?
能不能等一会？
Can you just wait a minute, honey?
妈妈！
MOM!
好吧，讲完再叫我听
All right. But give him back to me when you're done.
怎么了，杰夫？
What is it, Jeffrey?
嗨，爸爸
Hey, Dad.
对，那场比赛很精彩，我两次安打和一次四坏球
Yeah, it was a great game;I got two base hits and a walk.
对不起，妈，我给你添麻烦了
Sorry I cause you so much trouble, Mom.
我在这本书找到这些，你念念看
I want you to read something in this book I found.
这是本医学书，这些也许能解释你为何一直发出怪声
It's a medical book that might explain why you make all those noises.
我讨厌念书，妈…
I hate reading, Mom --
念吧
Read.
图雷特氏综合症
"Tourette Syndrome."
布莱德不就是这样吗？发出怪声和抽动…
That, that's Brad, isn't it? The noises and the twitches....
我需要进一步检查，但也许你是对的
I'll still need to do more tests but, umm, you could be right.
我们的方向可能错了
We may have been headed down the wrong road, here.
我从来没遇过图雷特氏症的病例
I've never actually seen a case of Tourette's before.
我多年的伴儿终于有了名字
So at last my Constant Companion had a name....
这本书上写说无药可医，但也许现在有了，这本书很旧
This says there's no cure. But that may have changed. This is an old book --
现在还是没有，科恩太太，我很抱歉
That hasn't changed, Mrs. Cohen. I'm very sorry.
哦，但医学界还在研究对吧？总有一天会找到的
Yeah, but they're still looking for a cure, right?
我是说，总有一天会找到的，不是吗？
I mean, they will find one, won't they?
他们…他们得找…
They - they...have to find...
没事了，妈，我们会好的，都会好的。
It's OK, Mom. We'll get through this, all right.
过来
Oh, come here.
看，所以这是有原因的，爸
SEE? There's a reason, Dad.
我不是故意在捣蛋
Joop, joop, I'm not being weird on purpose.
布莱德，我…
Listen, uh, Brad. l, um...
好了，我要说的话都说完了，再见
All right. Well, it's all I wanted to say. Bye.
我爸终于相信我了，但他对我没信心
Finally, my dad believed me. But he never believed in me.
不相信我会成功，不相信我能教书
That I would succeed.That I could teach.
喂？我是布莱德
Hello, this is Brad.
有狗？对，那是我的狗
A dog? Ahh, yes. Yes, ma'am, that's my dog.
好的，好，早上11点我可以到
Ahh, OK. Yes. Yes, I can be there 11am.
我的第一次面试…
My very first interview...
太好了，我没问题。好，谢谢你
Great. That sounds great. OK. Thank you.
我尽量不要反应过度，我克制了身体的抽动
I tried not to over-react. I help in my tics.
耶！太好了！
YES! Waffle, yes!
第一个电话之后，我又接到两个：三位校长，三次面试机会
After that first call, I got two more: three interviews with three principals.
无需多说，我这位多年的伙伴真是满腔热诚
Needless to say, my Constant Companion was more than a little enthusiastic.
哦，你只拿到了学士学位
Well, I see you only your bachelor's degree.
你有打算修硕士吗？
Are you planning to get your Master's?
有的，先生，一有机会我就去
Yes, sir. JOOP! As soon as I can.
哦，这不是必备条件啦
Well, we don't require it for entry level...
- 但，如果你是认真想…    - 我很认真
-but if you're serious about... -I'm very serious.
我想把教书当终身职业
I want to make teaching my life.
我发出这些怪声，是因为我有图雷特氏综合症
I, ahh, I make these noises because I have Tourette Syndrome.
我想跟你聊这件事
I'd like to tell you about it.
这是神经失调，我的大脑传送混乱的讯息给我的身体
It's a Neurological disorder where my brain sends mixed signals to my body.
就像打喷嚏一样，无法控制
It's like a sneeze. It's irrepressible.
过一、两个礼拜我再回复你
... a couple of weeks,and I'll give you a call.
- 好 - 好，谢谢你
-OK! -OK. Thank you very much.
- 谢谢   - 你保重
-Thanks. - Take care.
嗯，一振出局
Well. Strike one.
但我妈妈说过，不要轻言放弃
But, like Mom always said, don't ever give up.
我小时候，我妈从来没停止研究
When I was little, Mom never stopped researching because,
因为虽然我无药可医，但也许有办法过正常生活
while there was no cure, there might be ways to live a normal life.
妈，这是教堂
It's a church, Mom!
宝贝，不是要你去上圣经课啦
Honey, you're not going to have to get a Bible lesson.
这只是个互助团体
This is just a support group.
我非去不可吗？
Do I have to?
你要多和其他图雷特氏症患者接触
You need to connect with other people who have Tourette's.
看看他们是怎么过日子的，好不好？
Find out how they live with it. OK?
我们去试试看
Let's do it.
我不要进去
I'm not going in there --
宝贝…
Honey...
我从来没看过图雷特氏症患者
I'd never seen anyone with Tourette's before.
有人是眨眼睛和鼻子抽动
There were eye blinkers and nose twitchers.
有人是踏脚和颈部抽动，有人会大叫和咳嗽
Foot stompers and neck jerkers. Some of them yelped and coughed.
我在别人眼里就是这样吗？
Is this what I looked like to other people?
走吧，波波，我们是来学习的。开始学习吧
Come on, Bobo. We're here to learn. Let's start learning.
美国残障法案给我们权利
The Americans with Disabilities Act gives us
做想做的事或去想去的地方
the right to do anything or go anyplace that we want to.
但你去看电影试试看
But try going to a movie.
或是去音乐会或餐厅
Or a concert or a restaurant.
别人大吼着要你闭嘴，这时候法律根本没意义
That law doesn't mean anything when people are yelling at you to shut up.
我一回到家，爸妈就关窗户，拉上百叶窗
I come home and my parents close the windows and blinds
因为他们不想让邻居看到我的症状
because they don't want the neighbors to see me tic.
根本没人尝试着要被人接受
No one was even trying to be accepted.
大人都没工作，小孩都待在家
The audits were out of work.The kids stayed at home.
有件事我可以确定
I knew one thing...
我不想跟他们一样
I didn't want to be like them.
就连他球队的教练都不接受他
Even the coaches on his team wouldn't accept him.
我受够了
Oh, I'd had it.
你们也是在家自学吧？
Of course, you're home-schooling, too?
没有，布莱德和其他小孩一样上学
No. Brad goes to school like any other kid.
这些小孩和别的小孩不一样，上学对他们来说是浪费时间
These kids are not like any other kids;school's a waste of time for them.
他三年级我就让他休学了，免得我失去理智
I took him out at the third grade just to save my sanity.
听我的劝
You want my advice...
你也照做吧
...you'll do the same.
好，谢谢你
Yep. Thanks.
波波，我们走
Let's go, Bobo.
这是互助团体！哪里互助了？
It's supposed to be a support group! Where's the support?
难道要一辈子躲在家里吗？
Supposed to just hide away for the rest of your life?
对不起，我不该带你来这里，宝贝，忘了他们吧
I'm really so sorry that I brought you there, honey, let's just forget this --
妈，我不想忘了
I don't want to forget this, Mom.
那些人向图雷特氏症投降，但我是绝对不会放弃的
Those people let Tourette's win. I'm never gonna do that.
很难想像当时我才12岁
It's difficult to imagine that at the age of twelve
就领悟了人生真正的道理
I would find a genuine philosophy to live by.
但这就是那一刻，决定性的一刻
But here it was. This defining moment.
要永远都正面迎战逆境
To always face my adversity head on.
下次去面试前，我决定更坦白一点
When I went to my next interview, I decided to be even more up front.
先把我有图雷特氏症的事讲清楚
Get the Tourette's stuff out of the way first
再把我的教学理念告诉对方
and then dazzle 'em with my approach to teaching.
从你的资料看来做得很成功
you seem to have been very successful
虽然有图雷特氏症，
...in spite of your Tourette's.
我很努力地想当个好老师
I've worked very hard to become the best teacher I can be --
- 谢谢你抽空过来，我再通知你
Thank you for coming in.I'll let you know.
- 谢谢
Thanks.
坦白也没用啦
So much for being up front.
我第三次面试
For my third interview,
我决定完全不提我的图雷特氏症
I decided to discussing about my Tourette's at all.
我每个礼拜都会寄进度报告给每位学生的家长
Each week I like to send home a progress report to my students' parents.
我希望学生在学习过程中要多发表意见
Um, I like to give my students a voice in their learning --to be hands-on...
在课堂上要实践和互动
and interactive in the classroom...
同时也要让家长密切参与
but also to keep the parents closely involved!
罗恩，不提我的图雷特氏症是一大失策
Ron, it was a huge mistake not mentioning my Tourette's.
- 这就表示我想掩饰
It was, you know, I was trying to hide it --
- 没希望了啦
Fat chance.
- 好吧，这是负面想法
Okay, that's the negative --
- 不，你别再给自己压力了，你都压得我喘不过气了
No. The negative is you've gotta stop stressing out. You're stressing me out.
但正面的态度是
But the positive is that, hey,
别人好像不太在意嘛
the others didn't seem to have a problem with it, right?
我还是要等电话
I just, I gotta wait for a call.
正面的态度是你要跟我出去
The positive is you're coming out with me.
我的新女友有位室友
My new girlfriend -she has a roommate --
你能不能别再帮我牵线？
Will you stop trying to set me up?
等我准备好了就会去约会啦
When I am ready to date, I will date.
拜托，你的事她都听说了，她还是想认识你
Come on, she heard all about you; she still wants to meet you.
哦，多谢你的好意。听着，我想放松一下。好吗？
Oh thanks. Real kind. Listen, I want to relax. OK?
我想看勇士队比赛
I want to watch the Braves.
大家都想看勇士队比赛，去换衣服啦
We all want to watch the Braves. Get changed.
罗恩跟我说你正在积极找工作
So, Ron tells me that you're on a big job hunt.
进展得怎样？
How's it going?
还不错
Ahh, pretty good.
只是还没人录用我啦
Except no one's hired me yet.
他们大概是在抢着要我去吧
I guess they're all too busy fighting to get me.
你也会这样？
You do this?
给我留下了深刻的印象
I'm impressed by this.
- 本来就是    - 没想到你也会这样
-You should be.  -I was not expecting this.
了不起
That's amazing.
- 但我很厉害
But I'm pretty good.
- 你是啊
You are.
你真的是运动迷？
So you are really a sports fan?
- 对，超迷的，足球、垒球、网球
Ah, yes. Big time.Soccer, softball...tennis.
对，我大学时代经常运动，但还达不到职业水准啦
Yep, I played a lot in college, but I'm not good enough for the pros.
我也是，但我想跟他一样棒
I hear that because I wish I was good enough to be him.
- 跟谁？
Who?
- 他
Him.
你想当吉祥物？
Oh, you want to be a mascot?
- 他叫荷马…          - 荷马
-His name is Homer... -Homer.
- 这是我毕生的抱负
And it's a lifelong ambition.
- 好吧
OK. All right.
- 别转过去看      - 好
-Don't look now.  -OK.
现在别看，我们后面有个家伙
Don't look now, but there's this guy behind us
不知道他哪根筋不对，他一直盯着你看
and I don't know what his problem is.He keeps staring.
我经常看到那种表情
Ahh. I actually get that look a lot.
那是羡慕的眼神
It's a look of envy.
他在想要怎么跟我一样，发出这么酷的声音？
He's thinking, "How can l make cool noises like that guy?"
你还满乐观面对你的…
You have such a great attitude about your...
荷马再见！再见！  - 再见了，罗恩
Bye Homer! Bye. Bye, Ron!
- 再见
Bye.
荷马再见！勇士队加油！
Bye, Homer! Go, Braves!
进展得不错嘛，你有再约她出来吗？
So that must have gone well, huh? Did you ask her out again?
有，我约了，但我有第二次约会综合症
Yeah, I asked. But, it's second date syndrome.
我人很好，她也很风趣，只是…
You know, I'm a great guy, she had a lot of fun, but, umm...
你那些症状酷到她难以招架？
Your tics are just too cool for her?
不是啦，她说是因为我室友口臭
Actually, no, she says because my roommate's breath smells so bad.
- 什么意思？
What do you mean?
- 你明知故问
You know what I mean.
我是布莱德，嗨，爸
This is Brad. Ahh, hey, Dad.
没有，罗恩跟我说你打给我
Yeah, no, Ron --Ron told me you called.
只是我最近都忙着…
I just, ahh, you know, I've been so busy that, ah...
我还没吃午饭
No. I haven't had lunch yet.
好，没问题，你想约在哪儿？
All right, that sounds great. Where do you want to meet?
在爸爸工作的地方吃午饭
Lunch at Dad's work.
这样他就不必担心我发出怪声了
He wouldn't have to worry about my noises there.
- 还要再加桁架再跟我说，好吗？
Let me know if you need any more of those trusses, OK?
- 好
All right.
- 嗨
-Hey.
- 嗨，爸爸    - 你找到这里了
Hey, Dad. See you found your way.
- 对啊
Yeah.
去我办公室外面吃午饭吧，那里比较隐私一点
Let's grab lunch outside my office. Be a little more private.
好
All right.
黛安在问你几时会来我们家
Diane's wondering when you're gonna come by.
你大概在忙着找工作吧，有进展吗？
I guess you've been pretty busy with the job hunt. Any luck?
还在面试
Still interviewing.
面试得如何？
How's that going?
他们有没有介意你的…
Are they giving you any trouble with your, uh...?
你可以说出来…图雷特氏症
You can say the word, Dad: Tourette's.
有些人介意，有些人不会
Some of them are. Some of them aren't.
- 你的钱还够用吧？
How's your money holding out?
- 我不是来找你要钱的
I'm not asking you for money.
我知道，你从来不跟我要东西
I know that.You never ask me for anything.
对
No.
- 但你缺钱随时可以来我这边工作
But if you ever do get short,you know you gotta job with me here.
- 爸，我要教书
I'm going to teach, Dad.
OK?
我不能让任何事妨碍我做到
I can't let anything get in the way of that.
好吧，我只是觉得多点选择也没什么不好
OK. I'm jut saying there's nothing wrong...
免得有些事屡试不成时
...with keeping your options open in case things don't work out.
你看，除了教书之外还有很多其他工作
You know, there are other things besides teaching.
都不适合我
Not for me.
我爸永远不懂我的乐观
Dad could never understand my optimism.
就好像我小学毕业时
Like when I graduated to middle school.
我非常希望情况能有所改观
I was really hopeful that things would be different.
怎么了，布莱德？一个人吃饭？
What's the matter Brad? Eat alone?
新的开始，新的学校, 新的朋友
Make a fresh start. New school. New friends.
结果却一样
Same result.
今天我们要教的是分数
Today, we're going to be talking about fractions.
分数是你的好朋友
Fractions are your friend...
日常生活中经常用到分数
Use fractionsin every day life.
你只是不了解它
You just don't realize it.
比如你妈妈烤了一个馅饼
For example, say your mother bakes a pie.
她把馅饼切成几份
She cuts that pie.
科恩，你去校长室
Cohen! Just go to the principal's office.
这不是跟校长自我介绍的好方法
Not the best way to introduce myself to the principal.
布莱德，你觉得学校是干什么的地方？
What do you think a school's for, Brad?
- 抱歉，我一直打断课程…
I'm sorry I keep disrupting the class --
- 你没回答我的问题，学校是干嘛的？
You're not answering my question. What's a school for?
要教育学生，不是吗？
To educate, isn't it?
要用知识来打败无知
To use knowledge to wipe out ignorance?
学校的交响乐团今天下午有音乐会
The school orchestra's having a concert this afternoon.
你要去吗？
You planning on going?
我不去，我这个样子会打扰演出的
No, sir. My tics will ruin the music.
我希望你去
I want you to be there.
各位同学，请回座
Everybody just keep your seats for a minute, please.
谢谢，音乐会好听吗？
Thank you. Did you enjoy the concert?
表现得很好
Great job.
安静的时候有没有听到怪声？
Did you hear any noises during the quiet parts?
有
YES!
对，我也有听到
Yeah. So did l.
还满讨厌的，对吧？
They're pretty annoying, aren't they?
发出那些怪声的人是布莱德·科恩
The person making those noises is Brad Cohen.
布莱德，你上台
Come on up here, Brad.
你喜欢发出怪声惹人讨厌吗？
Do you like making noises and upsetting people, Brad?
不喜欢
No, sir.
那你干嘛要这样？
Then why do you do it?
因为我有图雷特氏综合症
Because I have Tourette Syndrome.
那是什么？
What's that?
我大脑有问题，所以会发出怪声
It's a thing in my brain that causes me to make weird noises.
但你想控制就能控制，对吧？
But you could control it if you wanted to, right?
不对，这是一种病
No, sir. It's a sickness.
怎么没接受治疗？
Well, why can't you just get cured?
没有药可以医
There isn't any cure.
你们不喜欢听到怪声，我也不喜欢发出怪声
I don't like making noises any more than you like hearing them.
我压力大的时候会更严重
They're even worse when I get stressed,
比如你们无法接受我不能控制
when you don't accept that I can't stop them.
但大家都接受我，我就不会那么严重了
But when I feel accepted,then they're not so bad.
我们能怎么做？
What can we do --
我指的是学校里的每一个人
and I mean everyone in this school -
我们能怎么帮你，布莱德？
What can we do to help you, Brad?
我只希望大家别用异样眼光看我
I just want to be treated like everybody else.
说得好，回去坐吧
Good job. Go sit down.
几句话 —— 点拨一下
A few words -- a little education -
就像开启了通往全新世界的大门
and it was like opening a door to a brand new world.
现在我知道将来无论何时、何地
Now some day, some way, I knew,
无论我有没有图雷特氏症
Tourette's or no Tourette's,
我都要当一个老师
I was going to be a teacher.
我别无选择，只能证明图雷特氏症
I had no choice but to prove that Tourette's would
永远不会打倒我
never get the best of me.
如果我放弃了，就等于是认同
lf I quit, I would be agreeingwith everyone
那些跟我说我想得太天真的人
who ever told me I was barking up the wrong tree.
抱歉，空调坏了，早就应该修好啦
Sorry about the air conditioning.Supposed to already be fixed by now.
没关系
That's all right.
你的履历还不错
Well, umm, your resume looks okay.
我们五年级也有个缺
And we do have an opening in fifth grade.
好
OK.
但我要告诉你，在这里教书可不轻松
But I do have to tell you:this is a tough place to work.
有几个头痛人物
We've got some really hard cases.
我视之为挑战
Well, I take that as a challenge.
我不认为有哪个小孩是没救的
I don't believe that any kid is hopeless.
他们都想学习，你永远不能放弃
You know, they all want to learn; you can't ever give up.
只需要...
Let me just...
只是要找对方法教导他们
You just gotta find the right way to teach them.
你喉咙有痰吗？
Ahh, you got something stuck in your throat?
要不要喝杯水？
Would you like a drink?
我有图雷特氏症。我想解释一下，
I have Tourette Syndrome. I'd like to tell you about it.
- 它是一种神经上的…    - 图雷特氏症？
-It's a neurological... - Tourette's?
是不是会骂脏话？
Isn't that where you yell out obscenities?
那是秽语症，这种症状很罕见
That's coprolalia,It's, ahh, it's a rare symptom
只有少部分的图雷特氏症患者会有
that a small percentage of people with Tourette's have.
- 我就没有这种症状    - 好吧，
-I don't have that.  - OK, listen.
他们没说你是身心障碍
They did not tell me that you were going to be handicapped.
你打算要怎么调教一群调皮的学生？
How do you expect to handle a bunch of wild students
在有这方面残障的情况下？
with a handicap like that?
嗯，教育他们啊
Well. By educating them.
让他们知道这是不必避讳的
By letting them know it's okay to talk about it.
- 可以提问题…                  - 这些学生会嘲笑你
-It's okay to ask questions...  - These students would laugh at you.
- 不会的…当他们明白
Not...not when they understand
- 这只是小状况…            - 好吧，我有看过
-it's simply a matter of... - OK. I have seen teachers
有残疾的老师
with disabilities before ...
…但从来没遇过像你这种的
...but never with what you've got.
我只是看不出你怎么能教一个班的学生
I just don't see how you could ever teach a class.
我能教，你看我的履历
I can teach! Look at my resume.
仔细看看！好吗？
Look at it! Ok?
我在教学上非常成功
I was very successful as a student teacher -
我的图雷特氏症从来就不是问题
my Tourette's never posed a problem!
我可以教书
I can teach!
好吧，反正我需要五年级的老师
OK. Bottom line: I need somebody now for fifth grade.
你想在这里教书
You want to teach here,
在课堂上就不能发出怪声
you're gonna have to refrain from making these noises in class.
- 你明白了吗？    - 谢谢你给我面试的机会
You know what?     - Thank you very much for the interview.
你不是想要这份工作吗？
But, don't you want the job -- ?
对，我真的非常想要
Yes, actually. I want it really bad.
但我再怎样也不替一个不关心他的学生的人工作
But I would never, ever work for a man who doesn't care about his students.
所以我要把我的资料带走，不再浪费你宝贵的时间
So, I'll take my portfolio and, ahh, and take no more of your time.
你老板人还真好啊
You got a great boss.
那是我最烂的一次面试经验
Well, it was the worst interview I've ever had.
他只看到我图雷特氏症的那一面
All he could see when he looked at me was my Tourette's.
他们都只看到这一面
That's all any of them see.
宝贝，他们没看到你是个好老师
Well, honey, if they can't see what a great teacher you'd be
那是他们的损失，不是你的错
that is their failure, not yours.
看起来是我的错
Well, it sure seems like my failure.
你要这么说，我也没办法啦
Well, if you say so. You know what?
要不然你干脆举白旗放弃，回家来吧，怎么样？
Why don't you just throw in the towel and come home, huh?
我会给你买张机票
I'll buy you a ticket.
- 我又没这样讲
I'm not saying that -
- 是吗？听上去就是这个意思啊
Really? That sounds like what you're saying.
听起来就是你被图雷特氏症打倒了
It sounds like you're letting Tourette's win.
- 我没让图雷特氏症打倒我
I am not letting Tourette's win!
- 真的吗？ - 对！
-Really?   -Yes, really!
我永远不会放弃，我只是…
Look, I'm never going to give up, I just...
我要找对学校才行
I have to find the right school.
你会的，波波，你会的
You will, Bobo. You will.
我的结论是：此事无关图雷特氏症
So, I decided it wasn't Tourette's.
我只是还没找到合适的学校
I just hadn't found the right school yet.
我要继续找，不找到好校长是不会放弃的
I'd keep barking, and I wasn't quitting until I found that principal.
我在地图上标出了每一所我还没面试过的学校
I made a map of every school where I hadn't interviewed.
如果校长不在，我就把履历给秘书或管理员
lf the Principal wasn't in, I'd give my resume to a secretary or a janitor,
请他们等校长回来后拿给他看
and ask them to drop it off when the principal returned.
我不在乎，我需要一份工作
I didn't care. I needed a job.
我没找到工作就不轻言罢休
I wasn't going to stop until I had one.
你得从基层做起
You'll be starting at the bottom,
但这样很正常，我也是白手起家
but that's no big deal, that's where I started.
你上班时间是7点到4点
And you're working 7 to 4.
我说过这是兼职性质的
I told you this is only part time.
我早上要面试，不能来上班
I need to keep mornings open for interviews.
学校不是早就开学了吗？
I thought that school had already started.
有些学校还没有
No, not all of them.
再看情况吧
Well, we'll see what happens.
这是你的干活工具，至少暂时的啦
Here are your tools of the trade - at least for the time being.
我说过了，要从基层做起
Like I said, at the bottom.
但这里的每份工作都很重要，天晓得
But every job is important here,and - who knows -
也许你做一做会爱上，只要你投入时间…
maybe you'll end up liking it. And if you put your time in...
- 我刚才讲的你没听见吗？
Didn't you hear what I just said?
我只在这里上班到我找到教职
I'm only working here until I get a teaching job --
那些东西都要搬去垃圾堆
All that stuff has to go in the dumpster.
聘任教师的季节快结束了
The hiring season was ending.
我的面试机会没了，学校已经开学
My interviews had dried up. School had started.
我没时间，也没钱…和希望
I was running out of time and money...and hope.
黛安
Diane.
我不指望你会来找我了，所以我直接来找你
I gave up on you ever coming to me, so I just came to you.
你在忙吗？
You busy?
这是我的继母黛安，她想用咸面包来拉拢我
It was my stepmom, Diane. Trying to build bridges with bagels.
你爸是凭双手打造他的事业
Your Dad built his business with his own two hands;
他希望你能参与，你不能怪他
you can't blame him for wanting you to be a part of it.
他只是尽力在作一个父亲的本分
He's just being a dad.
他希望你能融入他的生活
He wants you in his life.
你喜欢亚特兰大吗？有没有认识好女孩？
So how do you like Atlanta? You meet any nice girls?
我讲话都讲不到重点，对吧？
I'm just saying all the right things, huh?
我再帮你倒一杯
Let me get you a refill --
布莱德…
Brad. Brad,
你爸很爱你
your dad loves you...
非常爱你
...so much.
他只是不想看到你受伤
He just doesn't want to see you get hurt -
实际上最让我受伤的是：他从来就不接受真正的我
The only thing that hurts is the fact that he has never accepted who I am.
他脑海里有个完美儿子的形象
See, he's got this idea of a perfect son,
那个人很正常，做的都是正常的事
who is "normal" and does "normal" things.
而我永远也不可能达到那种“正常”
Well, I'm never gonna be "normal"
也许这些不是他想法，布莱德
Well, maybe that's not his idea, Brad.
而只是你的想法。你说得对，你是不正常
Maybe that's yours. And you're right, you are not normal.
你有教学的天分
You have this gift to teach,
但这些天分不是来自你的图雷特氏症
and it's not in spite of your Tourette's,
而是因为它本来就有
it's because of it.
我要走了
I have to go.
(现在球传到三垒，再传到一垒， 目前是一好一坏)
(准备投球，外侧过低的滑球)
(两好一坏)
嗨，我是布莱德
Hello, this is Brad.
嗯，是的
Ahh, yes.
对，我养了牧羊犬
That's a sheepdog.
对，布莱德，布莱德·科恩
Yep, Brad. Brad Cohen.
十点，我没问题
Ten o'clock is - is perfect for me.
好，好极了
Absolutely. OK, great.
(山景小学)
（举手，举手！）
Raise your hand. Raise your hand!
（你们要先举手，来！）
You gotta raise your hand! Come on.
你一定是布莱德·科恩吧
You must be Brad Cohen.
嗨！
Hi.
- 我是吉姆·欧贝，本校的校长
I'm Jim Ovbey; I'm the Principal around here. And...
希拉里·史崔卡，副校长
Hilarie Straka, Assistant Principal.
嗨
Hi.
进办公室聊，布莱德
Come on in the office, Brad.
听说你大老远从停车场过来
We heard you coming all the way from the parking lot.
听说你每间学校都跑遍了
Hear you've been making the rounds.
目前为止是25间，这是我的履历表
Twenty-five schools so far. And, uh, here's, here's my resume.
- 给我吧
-Oh. Here. -Oh.
我们待会儿再看，布莱德
We can look at that in a minute, Brad.
先进来，谈谈你为什么想当老师
Just come on in,tell us why you want to be a teacher.
好
OK.
嗯，这个，这是我毕生最大的愿望
Well, it's, uh,oh, it's, it's all I ever wanted to be.
从我还在念书到现在
Ever since I was in school.
一定有什么好老师激励了你
You must have had some pretty inspiring teachers.
是有位校长激励了我，麦尔先生
Ah, well. I had an inspiring principal -- Mr. Myer -
但我的老师们，他们
but my teachers, they really only
给我的启发都只是让我别像他们一样
inspired me to be the kind of teachers they never were.
那你要当怎样的老师？
What kind of teacher is that?
即使有一个学生与众不同，也要给他学习的机会
One who makes it possible for a kid to learn even if he's different.
我最好的老师应该算是图雷特氏症吧
In a way, the, the best teacher I ever had was my Tourette's.
- 布莱德，你可以不必谈这个
You, you don't have to talk about that, Brad.
- 没关系，我早就下定决心要直言不讳了
No, it's OK. I make a point of being open about it.
我从来不给学生们设限
It's, ah, never off-limits to my students.
他们随时可以问我任何问题
They can ask me anything they want about it at any time.
有些问题想必很有趣吧
You must get some pretty interesting questions.
对，有时候会牵涉到隐私
Oh, yeah. Sometimes it gets really personal.
希望这个问题对你不会太隐私
I hope this question isn't too personal, Brad.
你睡觉时会不会发出怪声？
Do you make those noises in your sleep?
我不知道，我睡着了啊
I don't know. I'm asleep.
不是啦，我睡觉时不会发出怪声
No. No, I don't tic in my sleep.
我放松时就不会发出怪声了，比如现在
When I'm relaxed, the noises give me a little bit of a break. Like just now.
好吧，我想多了解你的教学理念
Okay Brad. I want to hear more about your teaching philosophy...
好，我很乐意分享我的教学理念
Yeah. I'd love to tell you about my teaching philosophy.
我们聊了将近两个小时，这是我最棒的一次面试经验
We talked for nearly two hours, it was the best interview I'd ever had -
- 布莱德，很高兴认识你
Well, Brad, it was a pleasure to meet you.
- 我也是
You, too. You, too.
我们还要再面试几位老师
We've still got a few more teachers to interview.
一旦决定好就会通知你
But we'll let you know when we've made a decision.
好，太好了
Ok, great.
- 谢谢     - 谢谢两位
-Thank you. -Thank you...
我这多年的伙伴还是一样，警告我不要抱太大的失望
Still, my Constant Companion, as always, warned me not to get my hopes up.
但希望是很难戒掉的习惯
But hope is a hard habit to break.
我最后一次被找去和二年级的教职员面谈
I was called one last time to and asked come in and meet with the second grade staff.
你教过二年级？
Oh, so, you student-taught second grade?
我超爱二年级，那些小孩都像海绵一样
Oh, I love second grade! The kids are still so open-minded.
不管教他们什么都可以吸收
They're open to everything.
对，但还是要维持一点纪律吧？
Yes, but you do manage to maintain a little discipline, right?
不能让他们什么都吸收啊
While they're being so open?
对，我会让他们知道分寸的
I do let them know what the boundaries are. Yes.
布莱德，你认为你必须要教的，最重要的是什么？
So, Brad. What do you think is the most important thing you have to teach?
嗯……
Yeah. Ah, well.
除了识字的重要性和数学的价值以外
Besides the importance of reading and the value of math...
要教他们接纳自己
that it's okay to be yourself.
色彩涂到线框外也没关系，反正你就是这样的人
It's okay to color outside the lines if that's who you are.
那就可以忽略界线吗？
So it's okay to ignore the boundaries?
不是，我没有…
No, and I didn't...
我很抱歉，但你一直这么做下去
I'm sorry but how can you expect kids to learn
你觉得学生怎么还能学习？
when you're doing that all the time?
- 拜托，布兰妲…
Oh. Come on, Brenda --
- 不，不，没关系，这个问题很好
No, no, no. It's OK. It's a valid question.
我愿意回答
I want to answer it.
学生在了解我之前，有时候会觉得我很怪，甚至可怕
Before they know me, kids sometimes do think I'm just weird, even scary.
但等我跟他们解释了图雷特氏症
But, once I educate them about my Tourette's --
他们就会知道科恩老师是个普通人
and they see that Mr. Cohen is a real person
只是碰巧会发出一些怪声
who just happens to make funny noises,
然后他们就认同我是个好老师
well, then they accept me as a good teacher.
就像他们接受你们在座各位一样
Just like they accept all of you.
也许我们该向二年级的学生多学学
Well, maybe we should all try to be more like second-graders.
还有谁有问题要问科恩先生？
Does anyone have any other questions for Mr. Cohen?
布莱德，谢谢你抽空过来
Brad thanks for coming in.
校方会跟你联络，请你耐心等
The school will be in touch with you, so just be patient.
当你感觉到最后一次机会也搞砸了，要耐心等真的很难
It's hard to be patient when you feel as though you've blown your last chance.
而且耐心从来就不是我这个多年伙伴的强项
And patience never was my Constant Companion's strong suit --
那所学校应该没跟你联络吧
I'm guessing you never heard from that school.
还没有，他们还在面试
No, not yet. They're still interviewing.
我不担心
I'm not worried.
好吧
Okay.
你这是什么意思？
Is that supposed to mean?
我只是说“好吧”
I just said "okay".
我知道你的意思
I know what you mean
你是想：只有别人还有选择，就不会选中我
you don't think anybody would hire me if they had a choice.
你这是干什么？读心术吗？
What are you, a mind-reader now?
爸，今天是我最后一天上班
You know what, Dad? This is gonna be my last day here?
你为什么不等找到工作再说？
Well, why don't you wait and see if you got the job first?
我一定会找到工作的
I'm gonna get the job, Dad.
只是我要保持专注
I just have to stay focused.
你难道不能同时专注和实际吗？
Why can't you stay focused and realistic at the same time?
这样有什么不好？
What's wrong with that?
拿去吧
Here.
你没事吧？你这样会受伤啦
Whoa! Are you all right, man? You'll knock yourself out doing that!
如果你开车时这样怎么办？
What if that happens while you're driving?
我没事
I'm fine.
对啦，我不知道，你应该换个医生看看
Uh, yeah, I don't know. You oughta see another doctor.
我这辈子都在看医生，根本没用
I've seen doctors my whole life, Ron. OK? They don't help.
你不觉得要找个人看看吗？
Well, don't you think you need to see somebody?
我真的不需要
I really don't!
你就…
So, just.
There I was.
我又在等电话响了
Waiting for the phone to ring again.
我想说服自己，有好事会发生
I tried to convince myself something good would happen.
是我弟弟，我没想到他会来
My kid brother...not exactly what I had in mind.
- 你好啊，波波      - 杰夫！
- How are you doing, Bobo?  -Jeff,
你怎么会来？怎么没事先告诉我？
what, what are you doing here? Why didn't you tell me you were coming?
你身上穿的是短裤耶
You know you're in your boxers, right?
是老妈叫你来查我的勤吗？
Did, ah, Mom send you to check up on me?
干嘛？你需要别人查勤？
Why? You need checking up on?
不是啦，就…
No, but...
- 我的东西要放哪儿？
Where do I put my stuff?.
- 很好，你睡沙发
That's great. You get the couch.
这高尔夫球杆不错，新的吗？
Whoa! Nice clubs, are these new?
都是老爸的，他借我用
Ah. They're Dad's, he let me borrow them.
我想找你去打打高尔夫球
Thought maybe you and I could, ah, play a little golf.
他让我们去他那个俱乐部打
He got us a tee-time at his club.
你觉得怎样？这里要用3号铁杆？
So, what do you think? Three iron from here, little bro?
对了，谢谢你带我来打球
Hey, by the way,thanks for the round.
谢老爸吧，等一下…
Thank Dad. Oh, wait, forgot....
我忘了你们不讲话
...you guys aren't speaking.
我现在不想提到老爸
I don't want to talk about Dad right now.
你这样讲只是想激我啦
You're just saying that to rattle me because you know -
我一定会赢你
I'm going to beat you.
我是认真的，你跟爸该和好了啦
I'm serious, Brad, you and Dad gotta start getting along.
我们处得很好啊
We get along fine -
只要保持够远的距离就好了
as long as we keep it long distance.
所以你才搬来这里吗？为了保持够远的距离？
Is that why you moved down here? To keep it long distance?
你没什么好向他证明的吧？
I mean, it's not like you have anything to prove to him -- right?
现在怎样？你改当心理医生了？杰夫医生？
What are you now, Jeff, a shrink? Dr. Jeff, huh?
不好意思
I'm sorry, sir?
请你别再发出那种怪声
I'm going to have to ask you to stop making those noises.
- 老兄
Look, pal.
他不是故意的，他有…     - 没关系，我自己来就好了
-He's not doing it on purpose, he's got-  -No, no, no. I can handle it, Jeff.
知道了
I got it.
- 这样对其他要打球的人不公平
Look, it's just not fair to the other golfers.
- 我懂，只是我不能控制不发出怪声
No, I understand, that, umm, I can't help making these noises
因为我有图雷特氏症
because I have Tourette Syndrome.
这是一种神经性疾病，我来解释给你听
It's a neurological disorder; I'd like to tell you about it.
- 你应该离开这个球场
You're gonna have to leave the course.
我要替其他会员着想
I gotta think of the other members.
乔，别为难他了，他没怎么的
Hey, Joe. Leave the guy alone. He's fine.
嗨，老兄，我们俩来搭档吧，我约好的朋友没来
Hey, man. We're a twosome and our buddies don't appear to be showing.
要不要跟我们一起？
Would you like to join us?
- 如果你还不走，我就要叫保安了
lf you don't leave, I'm going to have to call security.
- 好的，好的      - 你…
-OK, OK. Umm...   -You...
谢谢你们，明年再来吧，好吗？
OK. Thanks, guys. Maybe next year, all right?
杰夫，我们走。 走了，老兄，谢谢
Jeff, come on. Come on, buddy. Thanks.
怎么了，杰夫？这种场面你又不是没见过
Come on, Jeff, it's not like you haven't seen it before.
大家都这么无知，你怎么受得了生活在这种世界？
How can you stand living in a world where everybody's so ignorant?
又不是每个人都这样，你也看到刚才那两个打球的人
Everybody's not. You saw those golfers back there.
他们还帮我讲话，我的人生中到处都有那样的人
They went to bat for me.My life is full of people like that.
我就很少遇到好人了
That's not always been my experience.
那是因为你老是为了挺我而打架
Well, that's because you're always getting into fights sticking up for me.
你和妈都是，你们老是在维护我
You and mom. You've always been there for me and my tics.
- 你知道吗？我开始觉得你很烦了。比赛看谁先到车上
You know what? You're beginning to"tick" me off... race you to the car.
- 什么？     - 笨蛋！
-Oh, yeah? What! Hey! HEY! - Sucker!
杰夫的来访让我暂时忘却烦恼，你作弊！
Jeff's visit did give me a break from my worries.
在他走后，我就接到学校的来电
And, right after he left,I got a call from the school.
校长要我去见他
The principal wanted to see me in his office.
跟小时候一样
Just like old times.
挺吵的吧？
Pretty noisy, huh?
但小朋友们都能接受，不是吗？
And yet somehow the kids manage, don't they?
是啊，他们都能接受
Yes, they do. They do.
希拉里和我跟老师们讨论过你的情况
Hilarie and I discussed you with the teachers.
我们聊到自己有多骄傲能教给孩子们
And, we talked about how proud we are of teaching our kids
永远不让任何事拦住他们的人生前路
to never let anything hold them back in life.
希拉里说如果我们要想说得漂亮
And, Hilarie said that if we're gonna talk the talk,
我们就得做得漂亮
we need to walk the walk.
她在等着带你去参观教室
She's waiting to show you your classroom.
欢迎你
Welcome.
二年级人很多，所以要多开一班
Second grade is overcrowded so we've had to create a new class.
你的学生都是从别班调来的
Your kids are being taken out of other rooms
有几个还搞不清楚状况
so some of them might be a little confused.
他们已进来这间学校三个礼拜了
They've already been in school for three weeks.
你的学生名单在那里
There's your student roster.
礼拜一就开始上课
The fun starts Monday, Brad.
有什么需要尽管告诉我
Let me know if there's anything you need.
我什么都需要
I need everything.
我低头看着那份学生名单
I looked down at that roster like I was announcing
就好像在宣布，明星棒球队的先发球员名单
the starting line-up for an all star baseball game.
- 希拉里，这是…谢谢你…
Hilarie, this is, thank you...
- 我们想说你可能会需要这些
Hey! We thought you might need these.
各位，都搬进来吧
Hey, everybody, bring them in.
先随便放，放好再来整理
Just put them down anywhere. We'll get them arranged.
给我，我来帮忙，谢谢
Here, let me help you with that.Thank you!
欢迎来山景小学
Welcome to Mountain View.
对，妈，这真是太好了
Yeah, Mom, it's phenomenal, but, you know,
但我好不容易才等到这一天
it's taken me so long to get here I still have to remind myself
现在我还得提醒自己一切才刚开始
that I'm just at the beginning.
宝贝，这是个天大的好消息！太好了
Honey, that is, that is wonderful news! That's wonderful.
是的，妈妈
Yes, yes, Mom.
这的确非常好，但是 -
It is absolutely wonderful, but, you know,
他们只跟我签约一年
they've only given me a contract for a year. OK.
- 我还得向他们证明他们没看错人
I still have to prove to them that they made the right choice --
- 宝贝，你先享受这一刻吧
Honey, listen, just take a moment to enjoy this.
天哪，我…
Oh my gosh. Oh my...
你有没有跟你爸讲？他一定会很骄傲的
Did you call your father? He is gonna be so proud of you.
我会告诉他的，妈妈，但现在
I will, Mom. But, you know, right now,
我得在两天之内准备好两个礼拜要做完的事
I literally have about two weeks of preparation to do in about two days.
既然我找到工作了
And, ah, you know, now that I have the job,
我就要认真开始进修硕士学位
I gotta really seriously start working on getting my Master's degree.
好啦，一次做一件事
OK, one thing at a time, all right?
学校里有没有漂亮的女老师？
Listen. Are there any cute teachers at that school?
- 妈！
Mom!
- 怎么嘛？我只是希望你快乐啊
What? I want you to be happy.
好啦
OK, all right, yes.
放心吧，我在用心了。先这样了，再见
Don't worry; I'm working on that, too. I gotta go. Goodbye.
(婚友联谊网)
你是布莱德吧
You must be Brad....
你是南茜吧
You must be Nancy.
嗨，我是布莱德
Hi, I'm Brad.
我知道
I know.
好吧，我只是有点紧张
Right. Of course. I guess I'm a little nervous.
请坐
Please.
这是我第一次和网友约会
This is my first time computer dating.
所以…   - 对
-So...  - Oh, yeah.
对，我也是，我妈觉得这很危险
Me too. My mom thinks it's dangerous.
是啊，谁知道你会遇到什么怪人
Well, yeah, I mean, you never know what kind of weirdo you might meet.
但你看起来蛮正常的
But you look pretty normal. So...
那就好，我真高兴
Good, I'm glad.
其实你比正常更好啦
Actually, look much better than normal.
谢谢你
Thank you.
那么，我觉得我们应该介绍下自己的情况吧
So, ahh, I guess we're just supposed to tell each other our life stories.
好啊
Umm, OK. Do, do...
那我能不能先来杯咖啡？
...you think I could get a, get a cup of coffee first?
- 咖啡？    - 对
-Cup of coffee. -Yeah.
- 好，没问题，马上来
Right. Yeah! Of course. Coming up.
- 谢谢
Thanks.
你要不要来个松饼蛋糕？
Ah. Do you want, like, a muffin?
我在节食
I'm on a diet.
但我好想吃松饼蛋糕
But I would love a muffin.
我室友快把我搞疯了
My roommate is driving me absolutely crazy.
她从来不整理床铺，衣服到处丢
She never makes her bed;she's got clothes everywhere;
她从早到晚都在大声听音乐
she's, like, always blasting her music...
但我每次听我的音乐
...night and day. But, of course, whenever I want to listen to my music,
她就说“你得放小声一点”
she's all, like, "you need to keep it down".
你都听什么音乐？
So what kind of music do you listen to?
- 就…嗯     - 什么？
-Well, umm,  -Yeah?
大部分都是老歌啦，尤其是史汀…
Mostly oldies stuff. Especially Sting -
我超爱史汀的
Oh, I love Sting!
- 麦当娜、邦·乔维
Madonna, Bon Jovi, you know
- 米利·维尼里？
Milli Vanilli...?
我好喜欢米利·维尼里
I love Milli Vanilli!
真的？
Really?
等一下，你也喜欢？
Wait. You too?
全世界大概只有我们两个人
We've gotta be the only two people on earth -
喜欢米利·维尼里吧
that love Milli Vanilli.
- 不会吧
You do not.
- 真的
Yeah!
我今天好开心，谢谢你
Well, I had a really nice time. Thank you.
我不应该吃那个松饼蛋糕啦
I shouldn't have had that muffin but...
- 但我很高兴能认识你
I really enjoyed meeting you.
- 我也是
Yeah, me too.
好了，谢谢你，布莱德
OK. Well, thanks again, Brad.
真搞不懂你！你说她很完美
I can't believe you! You said she was perfect --
- 她是很完美啊。我只是不想毁了这一切
She was perfect. I just didn't want to ruin it.
再约她见面会毁了一切？哦，对啦：再约会综合症
Oh, by asking to see her again? Oh, right: second date syndrome.
那你打算就这样过一生？第一次约会就结束？
So is that gonna be your life? Nothing but first and only dates?
这样你怎么可能有进一步的发展？
How do you ever expect to have a relationship?
也许就不要有啊
Maybe I don't.
(新邮件)
(南茜：我在听米利·维里尼，想到认识同好的你有多幸运)
(布莱德：我也是)
(欢迎来上科恩老师的课)
(科恩老师)
(不一样也没关系)
请进，进来吧，请进
Come on in. Get in there. Come on in.
怪胎！
Weirdo!
(图雷特氏综合症)
你们的老师有警告过，科恩老师会发出怪声吗？
Did your teachers warn you that Mr. Cohen makes funny noises?
有
Yeeesss.
- 她说你有图…图…
She said you have Tour...tour...
- 图雷特氏症
Tourette Syndrome.
好，想知道什么就问吧
OK. Anything you want to know about it,I want you to ask.
Yes.
会不会传染？
Is it catching...?
不会，绝对不会
No. Absolutely not.
这是天生的，像我一样
You have to be born with it,like I was.
会不会痛？
Does it hurt?
有时候，比如颈部抽搐就会痛
Well, sometimes,like when my neck jerks.
但发出怪声不会痛啦
But the noises do not hurt at all.
问得很好，继续问
These are great questions,keep 'em coming.
关于图雷特氏症的事都可以问我
And, it's okay to ask me anything -about Tourette's
请说
- yes?
- 你可以去看电影吗？
Can you go to movies?
- 我可以去看电影
Yes, I can go to movies,
但有时候会被赶出来，这让我觉得很难过
but sometimes I get kicked out and that makes me sad.
那只兔子叫什么名字？
What's the bunny's name?
威…威…威化
Waffle --
威 威 威化
Wa Wa Waffle!
它名字只是威化啦
His name is just Waffle!
好了
All right, guys.
还有关于图雷特氏症的疑问吗？
Any more questions about Tourette's?
有没有？
Anyone?
科恩老师，你能不能好起来？
Are they ever gonna make you well, Mr. Cohen?
目前是没有药可以治好图雷特氏症
Well. Right now there's no medicine that can cure Tourette's.
但没关系
But, it's okay.
因为我学会了接受，我不会让它毁了我的一生
Cuz I've learned to accept it and I don't let it run my life.
你有什么不能做的吗？比如不能吃东西？
What can't you do? Like...can you not eat?
我可以吃东西，而且我很会吃哦
I can eat. OK, I eat a lot.
其实别人能做的事我都能做
In fact, I can do anything anybody else can do except
科恩老师只有一件事不能做
there is one thing that Mr. Cohen can never do.
- 什么？  - 不，我不能说
What?     - No. I can't
- 是什么？     - 不，我不能说
What is it?    - No. I can't
- 告诉我们嘛
- Tell us
科恩老师永远不能玩
Mr. Cohen can never play -
捉迷藏
hide and go seek.
- 为什么你不能玩捉迷藏？
Why can't you play hide and seek?
- 因为会被人听到啦，笨蛋
Cause they'd hear him, stupid.
答对了，但用这样的字眼是不对的
Well, that's the right answer but it's the wrong words
因为在科恩老师班上不能骂人
because there won't be any name- calling in Mr. Cohen's class,
- 你好，请问你要去哪儿？
Excuse me? Where are you going?
- 上厕所
Bathroom.
- 你叫什么名字？
And what's your name?
- 托马斯
Thomas.
好，托马斯，如果你要离开座位
OK. Well, Thomas,if you want to leave your seat,
就要先征求我的同意
you have to ask for permission.
怪胎
Weirdo.
- 科恩老师再见
Bye, Mr. Cohen.
- 盖伦再见
Bye, Gaylon.
科恩老师再见
Good bye, Mr. Cohen.
再见，海瑟，明天见
Bye Heather, I'll see you tomorrow.
我好喜欢上你的课，科恩老师
I really like your class, Mr. Cohen!
谢谢你，阿曼达  - 莱特先生，你好吗？
Oh, well, thank you, Amanda! How are you doing Mr. Wright?
- 我很好
I'm fine.
四眼田鸡！
Four eyes!
- 四眼田鸡
- 口香糖给我   - 不要过来！
-Gimme gum!   -Leave me alone!
好了，你抓住他，托马斯
OK, take him, Thomas.
伊莱！托马斯！你们谁想帮我？
Eli! Thomas! Which one of you guys thinks that you can help me? Huh?
我要！我要！
I can, I can!
好，这样吧
All right, all right. Here's the deal.
我这个球要放回篮子里
I need to get this ball and put it back in that bin.
你们来猜拳决定
Why don't you guys shoot for it?
剪刀、石头、布
Rock, paper, scissor, shoot!
好，伊莱，你今天赢了
Whoa! All right, Eli. You win today. Boom!
- 哎哟！
Ah, man!
- 没关系啦，托马斯，你去帮他
It's OK, Thomas, you can help him.
抱歉，我把托马斯丢给了你  但他实在闹得我不能上课
Sorry I stuck you with Thomas,but he was making my class impossible.
他有一大堆问题：注意力缺陷症、过动症
He's got a whole alphabet of problems:ADD, ADHD, OCD.
听我的劝，把他转去特教班吧
You want my advice,you'll pass him on to Special Ed.
不行
No.
我不能这么做
I can't, ah, I can't do that.
等他妨碍你几堂课你就知道了
Oh. See how you feel after he's trashed a few classes.
没事的啦  我只需要适应一下
I'll be all right.I just need to get settled.
我等不及明天了
I can't wait for tomorrow.
好吧
OK.
你比我的喇叭还要吵啦
You make more noise than my air horn.
你好像是有图雷特氏症吧
Sounds like you got healthy case of Tourette's.
开玩笑的啦，我有个同事也有图雷特氏症
I was just kidding with you, son. I've got a dispatcher buddy with TS.
你有要搬的东西就找玛克辛吧
You ever need any cross-country hauling, just call for Maxine.
你有名片吗？
Hey, umm. Do you have a card?
我不是认真的啦，小子，除非你是从事运输业
I wasn't being serious, son. Unless you're in the shipping business.
不是，我是二年级的老师
Nah, I teach second grade.
(玛克辛的红卡车)
- 这是我的名片     - 好
-Here's the card.  - All right.
玛克辛给了我一个地理课的好主意
Maxine gave me a great idea for a geography lesson.
谢谢你，玛克辛
Thank you so much, Maxine.
- 不客气
You're welcome.
- 小心开车
Safe trucking.
我发现自己的关注点都放在教书上了
I found myself focusing on teaching all the time.
几乎啦
Well, almost...
你知不知道我刚才发现什么？
You know what I just realized?
什么？
What?
所有的鸭子都有图雷特氏症
All ducks have Tourette's.
为什么？
Why is that?
我不知道，我跟它们是同类
I don't know.We're birds of a feather.
- 你一点也不介意吧？
So, it really doesn't bother you,does it?
- 什么？
What?
你明知故问，我的图雷特氏症啊，我发出的怪声
You know what. My Tourette's... my noises.
跟别的男人比起来就没什么啦
Not when I compare them to the noises other guys make.
就是吹牛、讲话超大声、自我中心、一堆自大的白痴
You know, like, braggers, loud-talkers, egocentric, humor-challenged idiots.
真的不会，你的怪声我毫不介意
Seriously, no.Your noises don't bother me at all.
只要你一直逗我笑就好了
As long as you keep me laughing.
别这样讲，你知道我压力大会怎样
Well, don't say that.You know how I get under pressure.
对不起
Oh, I'm sorry.
我爸早就知道我会嫁给逗我笑的人
My Dad has always said I was going to marry somebody who made me laugh.
我这样讲没什么特别的用意
Not that that has anything to do with anything.
讲话嘛
Say something.
呱！
Quack.
别笑，我呱得很认真
Hey. Don't laugh.That was a serious quack.
我有吓到你喔
I got you though.
- 科恩老师
Mr. Cohen!
- 嗨
Hey!
我妈要我问你可不可以
My Mom said to ask if it's okay.
什么可不可以，海瑟？
Is what okay, Heather?
这个可不可以给威化吃
lf I give this to Waffle.
告诉你妈妈我说可以
You tell your Mom that I said that's fine. OK?
- 他说可以吗？
Did he say it was OK?
- 可以
Yeah.
感觉好吗？
Feel OK?
嗯
Um-Hmm.
- 是喔，我爱你
Yeah? I love you.
- 我也爱你
I love you, too.
- 你今天要乖哦
You have a good day, OK?
- 好
OK!
- 我放学再来接你
I'll see you right after school.
- 好，再见
OK. Bye-bye.
阿曼达？你还好吧？
Amanda? Is everything all right?
我想上你的课，科恩老师
I wanna be in your class, Mr. Cohen.
你就在我班上啊，阿曼达
You are in my class, Amanda.
没了，他叫学校把我转到别班
No. He made them take me out --
我放学后再来接你
See you after school, honey. OK?
不公平！
It's not fair!
没事吧？我是阿曼达的老师科恩
Is everything OK? I'm Amanda's teacher, Mr. Cohen.
我们昨天见过
-We met yesterday. -Oh, no, no, no.
没事，没什么问题啦
There's nothing wrong.
我只是要为我女儿着想
I just have to do what's right for my daughter.
走吧，阿曼达
Come on, Amanda.
走了啦
Come on.
他担心阿曼达不能专心
He's concerned about Amanda's ability to concentrate.
他觉得你是她学习上的阻碍
He just thought that you'd make it a little harder for her.
他不能给我一次机会吗？
Can't he just give me a chance?
学期才刚开始
We've only just started.
- 我有讲了
I pointed that out.
- 然后呢？
And?
他说他很同情
He said he was sympathetic
但他说阿曼达需要正常的老师
but that Amanda needs -- as he put it -a "normal teacher."
布莱德，你别放在心上，家长是老师最难解的课题
Don't take it to heart, Brad. Parents are the hardest part of the job.
好，有谁知道玛克辛和她的大红卡车
All right, who can tell me the names of the capitals Maxine
要经过哪几州的首府？ 有谁知道？
and her big red truck have passed through? Anybody?
不好意思…天哪，
Oh, all these hands! Excuse me. Excuse me.
我该选谁？
Ah, man. Who do I choose?
我不知道耶
I don't know.
海瑟
Heather.
亚特兰大、纳什维尔、斯普林菲尔德
Atlanta...Nashville...um... Springfield?
答对了，很多人都以为是芝加哥
That's great! Because a lot of people think it's Chicago.
斯普林菲尔德是在这儿吧？
And, ah, this is Springfield, right?
不对！
Noooo.
那是印地安纳波利斯
That's Indianapolis.
答对了
Oh, that's right!
我在想什么啊  这才是斯普林菲尔德
So, what am I thinking? This is Springfield.
不对！
NO!
那是哥伦布，斯普林菲尔德在这里，科恩老师
That's Columbus! Springfield's over there, Mr. Cohen.
在哪里，伊莱？是在这里吗？
Where is it, Eli? Is it over here?
不是！
Nooo!
斯普林菲尔德在哪里？
Where is Springfield?
我不知道，你们要指给我看
I don't know.You guys have to point it out to me.
指给我看…
Point it out. Point it out.
我看不到啊
I don't see it there.
我看到了
Ahh! I see it!
你们是说这才是斯普林菲尔德吧？
You're telling me that this is Springfield. Right?
对！
YES!
我没同意你离开座位，托马斯
You don't have permission to leave your seat, Thomas.
对，科恩老师的后脑勺有长眼睛
That's right. Mr. Cohen has eyes in the back of his head.
请你回去坐好  下次要先问我
Go back and sit down, please.And next time, ask.
但我要削铅笔啊
But I need to sharpen my pencil.
回来坐好，托马斯
Now, Thomas.
好了
All right, now.
玛克辛和她的大红卡车礼拜二要去哪里？
Where's Maxine and her bug red truck going to be on Tuesday?
我！我！
ME! ME!
明天一大早再见了，大卫
See you bright early tomorrow, David.
好了，记得要走路哦
All right. Hey. Remember to walk.
我很喜欢你的帽子，科恩老师
I really like your hat, Mr. Cohen.
谢谢你，海瑟，我喜欢你的发型
Well, thank you, Heather.I like your hair.
我头发很短是因为我吃的药啦
It's just short 'cause of the medicine.
再见
Bye.
宝贝！
Hey, honey!
妈妈
Hi, Mom.
你可以等我一下吗？
Can you wait right here for just a minute?
- 好啊  - 好
-Sure. -OK.
- 嗨，我早就想找你谈海瑟的事了
Hey, umm. I've been meaning to come and speak to you about Heather.
- 我想我大概知道
I think I know....
对，我们刚开始不想告诉别人
Yeah, umm. We were just reluctant to tell anybody at first.
当然别人迟早会看到化疗的影响
Of course it was only a matter of time before the chemo became obvious, so ...
她会好起来吗？
Is she, ah, going to be okay...?
海瑟很喜欢上你的课
Umm. Heather just loves your class.
她每天都等不及要来上学
She can't wait to get to school every day.
如果你能帮我保密更久一点  我会很感激你
And, umm, I'd be grateful if you kept our secret a little longer.
我只是不希望她被排挤
I just don't want her to be singled out.
好
Yeah.
谢谢你，好了，宝贝女儿  我们走吧
Thanks. All right, baby girl. Let's go.
再见
Bye!
要不要去吃冰淇淋？
How about...an ice cream?
- 好啊
Yeah!
- 好
OK.
你觉得怎样？
Uh-oh. What do you think?What do you think?
- 不要，那顶我已经有了
I already have that one.
但你戴起来很好看
Looks great on you, though.
怎么了？
Hey, what's wrong?
没事，我只是专心在想学校的事
Oh, nothing, I'm just focusing on school stuff.
- 能不能专心在我身上一下？
Can you focus on me for a minute?
- 对不起
Sorry.
嘿！你试戴这顶
Hey, hey, hey! Try this one on!
会让你心情变好
It'll make you feel better.
- 好
-Yeah. -OK. Yes.
- 怎么样？  - 很好
- Yeah?    -Yes!
- 真的？  - 天哪，你戴起来很好看
-Really?  -Oh my goodness, this suits you.
你大概没想到吧
More than you know.
我决定要去修硕士学位了
I've, ah, decided it's time to go for my master's degree.
哇
Wow.
意思是你要搬走了吗？
Wow, does that,does that mean you'll be going away?
没有，我念本地的学校
No. I'd go locally.
我要先通过研究所的入学考试啦
Anyhow, I have to pass the entrance test to graduate school first, so...
等一下，像学力测验那样吗？
Oh, wait. Isn't that like the SATs?
你要和很多人，在一个大房间里考试？
Do you have to take that in a big room with a lot of people?
- 对，他们说我可以自己一个房间
Yeah. They said I could have a room all to myself.
- 那就好
Ah, good.
图雷特氏症患者是有特权的
Tourette's does have its privileges.
我搬走你会难过吗？
Would it bother you if I did go away...?
当然会了，你是在开玩笑吧？
Of course it would. Are you kidding me?
- 走啦    - 不信你说的
Get out of here.
- 过来，我有东西要给你看         - 神经病
- Come here, I want to show you something.   - Crazy.
下一位
Next!
嗨，布莱德·科恩
Hey, ah, chchchch, Brad Cohen.
布莱德·科恩
Brad Cohen.
找到了，科恩先生
Here you are, Mr. Cohen.
好了，请你带着这份资料进去
All right, I need you take this packet, and I need you to go right in there.
我应该要有特殊的考场
Oh, I'm supposed to have special accommodations --
我没有看到上面有什么标注哦
I don't have any notation of that.
我是说，今天大家都要在同等条件下考试
I mean, everybody tests under the same conditions today.
好吧，我有打电话问过
OK, yeah, but I called and they said -
他们说
They said-
他们说我可以有单独的空间
They said that I could have a, ah, space to myself
这样吧，你去问问负责人
You know what? I need you to talk to the administrator about that.
他的办公室在那边
His office is right over there.
我不能破例
I can't make an exception...
我们没遇过这种事
...we're not set up that way -
他们同意给我特殊的个人考场
They promised and I have the right to special testing accommodations --
你有残疾我很抱歉，但我帮不上忙
Listen, I'm sorry about your disability but there isn't anything I can do.
如果你想参加考试，就得马上进去
lf you want to take the test, you need to go in there now --
你看看我，有我在那里面，谁还能专心考试？
Look at me! How could anybody possibly concentrate if I'm in that room?
听着，现在我得现在开考了
Listen, I have to start the exam, now.
你要我打电话给你的医生吗？
Do you need me to call you a doctor...?
或者你要请谁来帮忙？
Isn't there anyone you can call for help?
布莱德，冷静点，我没听懂
Brad, calm down, I can't understand you...
他们说你可以单独考试？
Well, they said you could take it alone?
- 好，没问题，我马上过去
OK. All right. No problem. I'll be right there.
- 出了什么事吗？
Has something happened?
你可以考试了，有单独的考场
You can take the test.And you'll have a room to yourself.
你跟他们说了什么？
What did you say to them?
关键字：我要告他们
The magic word: lawsuit.
我该去上班了
I've gotta get to work.
- 嘿，爸
Hey, Dad.
- 什么事？
Yeah?
谢谢你
Thanks.
祝你考试顺利
Good luck on the test.
事实证明，我需要的不只是爸爸的祝福，我需要的是时间。
As it turned out, I needed more than just Dad's good luck. I needed time.
时间有限，我的图雷特氏症不配合
With the clock, and my Tourette's, ticking away.
我来不及把考题全部写完
I failed to get all the way through the test.
很好，托马斯，我以你为傲
Good job, guys.Thomas I am so proud of you.
谢谢你，科恩老师
Thank you, Mr. Cohen.
你的火鸡好漂亮，海瑟
Wow! Look at that turkey, Heather.
谢谢老师
Thank you.
你今年感恩节会过得很热闹吗？
So. Are you gonna have a big Thanksgiving this year?
会啊，妈妈说爷爷奶奶都要来
Uh-huh. Mom says all my grandparents are gonna come.
好特别哦
Well, that sounds special.
只是他们会哭
'Cept when they cry.
他们都偷哭，但我每次都有看到
They try to hide itbut I always see them.
我可以摸威化吗？
Can I pet Waffle?
你当然可以摸威化
You bet you can pet Waffle.
科恩老师，你要过感恩节吗？
Are you gonna have a good Thanksgiving,Mr. Cohen?
要啊，我和威化要去圣路易看我妈
Yes, I am. Me and Waffle are going to take a little trip
圣路易看我妈
to see my Mom in St. Louis.
我知道圣路易在哪儿
I know where that is!
是喔，太好了，海瑟 - 就是在那里
Well, that is super, Heather. That's exactly where it is.
请你帮我一个忙，好吗？
Now, do me a favor, will you?
- 我要请你照顾我的好朋友威化
And I'm going to trust you to take good care of my friend Waffle. All right?
- 好啊
Sure.
我马上就回来
And I will be right back.
嗨，阿曼达，你不用上课吗？
Hi, Amanda. Shouldn't you ja be in your class?
好了，走吧，我陪你走回教室
All right. Come on,I'll walk you to your room.
为什么我不能在你班上？
Why can't I be in your class, Mr. Cohen?
你爸爸都是为了你好
Well, ah. Your father had to do what was best for you, Amanda.
而且你有个很好的老师
And you know what? You've got a great teacher.
好吧，再见了，科恩老师
OK... See you later, Mr. Cohen.
被抓到了
Busted.
托马斯，那些字你从哪儿学来的？
Where did you learn those words, Thomas?
没我的同意，你不能离开教室
You know you're not supposed to leave the class without asking.
你要把门擦干净
Well, you're going to clean that up.
然后我要处罚你不能下课
And then, ah, you're on detention: no recess.
但你的拼字真是一级棒
But you do get an "A" for spelling.
你不翻开书就不能念了啊
You can't read it if you don't open it, Thomas.
我讨厌念书
I hate reading.
- 我也是
So do l.
- 你也是？
You do?
真的，要我念书是很困难的
Yeah. Reading's really hard for me.
对你来说才不难，你是老师
It's not hard for you.You're a teacher.
要不要打赌？我们来玩个游戏
You wanna bet? Let's play a game.
假装你是科恩老师要念书，而我是图雷特氏综合症
You be Mr. Cohen trying to read; And I'll be Tourette Syndrome. OK?
你念这一页
Read this page.
“很久以前…”
"Once upon a time" --
继续念
Keep reading.
“很久以前有一个”…好痒哦
"...upon a time, there was a" -That itches.
会痒吗？好了，继续念
Does it itch a little bit? All right. Keep reading.
“有一个…”
"...there was a..."
托马斯！
Hey, Thomas!
好了，很难吧？
All right. That's hard, isn't it?
这样很难专心
It's hard to concentrate.
念书对我来说就是这么困难
That's how hard reading is for me.
对你来说没那么难吧？
It's not that hard for you, is it?
对，对我来说很简单
No. It's easy for me.
可是你讨厌书要怎么当老师？
But...how can you be a teacher if you hate books?
讨厌书？ 我不讨厌书啊，世界上的所有知识都在书里
Hate books? I don't hate books. Everything in the world is in books.
只是我要多费点心力才能学到
I just have to work extra hard to get it out.
我不会放弃你的
I'm not going to give up on you, buddy. OK?
我也不会让你放弃自己
And I'm not going to let you give up on yourself.
继续念，从这里开始
Now keep reading. Right here.
很久以前有个…
"Once upon a time there was a" --
魔…魔…
Mag-magi...
魔法师
Magician.
“有个魔法师，他遇到一个小男孩
"A magician who met a small boy.
这个小男孩想把一把长剑，从石头里拔出来
A small boy who was trying to pull a big sword out of a big rock.
好奇怪
Weird.
石头里怎么会有剑？
Why would a sword be in a rock?
我不知道  但你再念下去就会知道了
Well, I don't know, but if you, ah,keep reading, you might just find out.
“魔法师跟小男孩说，把剑从石头里拔出来的人
"The magician told the small boy that whoever could pull the sword out of
就会成为真正的国王”
the rock would be the true king.'' --
好酷哦
Cool.
继续念啊，后来呢？
Keep going. What happens next?
(圣路易，再过12个出口，诺伍广场)
怎么了？
Hey. What's wrong?
我好紧张
Oh, I'm so nervous.
有什么好紧张的？你只是去见我妈啊
What's there to be nervous about? You're just gonna meet my Mom -
- 谢谢，你还真会安慰人
Thank you. That's, that's helpful.
- 还有杰夫…还有我的舅舅阿姨们…
-- And Jeff... and my aunts and uncles...
还有我这辈子最爱的每一个亲人
and anybody I've ever loved...in my entire life.
你要作好准备，场面会很大
Prepare your self. This is big.
我准备好了，干嘛要我准备？
I'm ready. Why do I have to prepare myself?.
对，你要作好准备
That's right. Prepare yourself.
你来了啊
Oh, you're here!
嗨！我终于见到南茜了
Oh, hi! I can't believe I'm finally meeting Nancy.
你比我想像中更漂亮
Oh! You're even prettier than I thought --
布莱德经常提到你，科恩太太
Brad has told me so much about you,Mrs. Cohen -
叫我艾伦
Oh, Ellen.
他都没什么提到你啦
Well, that's more than he tells me about you -
什么？我经常跟你提到南茜啊
Wha-what! What? I tell you all about Nancy.
你都没告诉我实话啦
Oh, you never tell me the real stuff.
走吧，南茜 - 波波，拿行李
Come on, Nancy --Bobo, get the bags, honey.
- 对，波波，快去拿
Yes, Bobo. Get on that.
- 你累不累？
So, are you exhausted?
- 不累
No.
很好，因为我们约了一个小时以后要修指甲
Oh, good. Because we've got a pedicure appointment in an hour.
Oh.
- 这位是南茜     - 嗨
-This is Nancy.  -Hi.
- 我跟你说的就是她    - 幸会
- Who I was telling you about. -So, nice to meet you.
- 不行，等一下，过来见见珍娜
And, no, wait, Janet. Here, come and meet Janet.
- 好啊，嗨   - 南茜，还有一个人…
-OK. Hi!     - Nancy. And one other person...
妈妈有点过头了  她想给南茜回家的感觉
Mom's going a little overboard making  Nancy feel like family.
有可能吗？她会变成家人吗？
Is that a possibility? Her being family?
我不知道，你也知道的
I don't know. I mean, you know,
我就不…不…不…
I know but I don't, I don't,I don't, I don't...
好，你是认真的。她见过老爸了吗？
Oh, yeah. It's, it's serious. Has she met Dad?
没有，还没有…
No! No, no, no, no...
你还在等什么？
Well, what are you waiting for?
少管闲事啦
Hey. Back off, will'ya?
结果他跌倒了
... He ended up falling flat
头去撞到人行道
and then he hit his head straight against the curb.
还脑震荡
Gave himself a concussion.
失陪一下，厨房需要南茜
Well, You'll excuse me, Nancy's needed in the kitchen.
我要借用她一下
I'm just going to steal her for one second.
- 厨房需要我
Needed in the kitchen.
- 好
OK.
你来救我吗？我不需要你救啦
Are you rescuing me? Because I don't need rescuing --
我需要
I do.
出了什么事？
What's going on -- ?
你修指甲好玩吗？
How was your pedicure?
如果你想知道
lf you're wondering
我跟你妈聊什么，我们聊的是你啦
what did your Mom and I talked about, we talked about you.
还有我们
And us.
怎么了吗？
Is something wrong?
我只是在想
I was just wondering,
应不应该告诉你…
if I told you,
我爱你
I love you.
我好害怕
I mean, it just, it scares me. Right?
我从来没想过这件事
I never thought about it before.
我从来就不敢去想
I never dared think about it.
布莱德…
Look, Brad.
她知道你会发出怪声，她不介意
She understands about your noises,she doesn't care.
你让她快乐
You know, you make her happy, Brad -
这是她告诉我的  你逗她笑
she told me that, Brad.You make her laugh.
如果有一天她不笑了怎么办？
Well, what if one day she stops laughing?
如果有一天她不想再跟我这种…
What if one day she gets fed up of living with someone who -
我只是…我不想伤害她，妈
I just, I don't want to hurt her,Mom....
也许是你不想受伤吧
Maybe you don't want to get hurt.
都有啦
Both.
只有一件事会伤害你们
The only thing that can hurt either of you:
那就是你让图雷特氏症把她赶走
is if you let Tourette's drive her away from you.
不要被它打败
lf you let it win.
海瑟的妈妈打电话来
Heather's mother had called to say
说海瑟没办法再上学了
Heather was no longer able to attend school.
全班同学都在想办法替她打气
So, the class all pitched in to cheer her up --
你看看这张桌子
Oh, wow. Look at this table.
看起来很棒嘛
It looks very good.
这个看起来也很棒
Ah, this looks great over here.
(我爱海瑟)
(海瑟)
过了几个礼拜  我们大家害怕的消息来了
The news we'd all been dreading came a few weeks later....
嗨
Hey.
- 嗨，科恩老师
Hi, Mr. Cohen.
- 你好，亨利
What's up, Henry.
嗨
Hi.
- 嗨，伊莱  - 嗨，科恩老师
-Hey, Eli. -Hi, Mr. Cohen.
- 嗨，科恩老师
Hey, Mr. Cohen.
- 你好，盖伦
What's up, Gaylon?
- 这是我爷爷奶奶 詹姆斯和雪莉
These are my grandparents,James and Shirley.
仪式就要开始了
Sir, they're about to start the service.
你先进去吧
You go ahead.
科恩老师？ 你不进来吗？
Mr. Cohen? Aren't you coming in?
很抱歉，我很想进去
I'm sorry... I thought I could but I...
但我会干扰仪式的进行
I think I'd be too disruptive.
你改变了海瑟的一生
You made such a huge difference in Heather's life.
你是她最喜欢的老师
You were her favorite teacher.
请你务必送她最后一程
Please, don't leave without saying goodbye to her.
(复活节快乐)
(乔治亚州)
好了，托马斯，你那一组的词叫什么？
Okay, Thomas... what is your team's word?
“怪胎”
Weird!
“怪胎”。不是托马斯那一组的人，有谁知道“怪胎”是什么意思？
Weird. Anybody not on Thomas's team know what that word means?
奇怪
Strange.
诡异
Creepy.
恐怖
Scary.
很好
Very good.
- 谁会用“奇怪”造句？
Who can use the word weird in a sentence?
- 我！我！
Me, oh, me!
25、30、35、40。绑辫子的女生，50！盖伦！
25, 30, 35, 40. The girl in pigtails. 50! Gaylon!
“我喜欢奇怪的电影”。抱歉，科恩老师
"I like weird movies." Sorry, Mr. Cohen.
我知道你不能去看电影
I know you can't go to them
因为你会被戏院赶出来
because you get thrown out of the movie theater.
没关系，盖伦
Well, that's OK, Gaylon.
因为我可以租片子回家看
Boom. Because I can rent movies.
而且我喜欢奇怪的电影
And I also like weird movies.
所以“奇怪”是个好字
So weird is a good word, right?
可如果有人跟你说：“喂！”
But what if someone comes up to you and they say,"Hey, you!
“你，我在跟你讲话。你好奇怪”
Yeah, you. I'm talking to you. You're weird.
- 这时它还是个好词吗？
Is it still a good word?
- 不是
Noooo.
什么声音？
What, what's that?
好了，大家都回座位上坐好
OK, everyone, stay in your seat.
是玛克辛和大红卡车
It's Maxine and big Red.
科恩老师，我们可以去看吗？
Mr. Cohen, can't we go see them?
好，但大家都要小声一点
Okay, but everyone... inside voices...
到门口排好队，不准用跑的
Everyone line up by the door and no running.
没问题。好啊。伊莱，上去啊
You got it. Yeah. Exactly. Eli, get in there, man.
没关系，但你要小心
All right, but be careful.
你觉得怎样？满酷的吧？
So, what do you think of it?Pretty cool, huh?
伊莱，我不是说了吗？好了，不准按喇叭
Eli! What did I tell you? All right, no pulling the horn.
否则就全部都下来
Or else you guys are coming down.
对不起，玛克辛
Sorry, Maxine.
没关系啦
That's all right.
小孩就是小孩
Kids will be kids.
对，永远是这样
Yes, yeah. Yeah, they will.
他们相处得还好吧？
They still getting along?
看起来是不错
Well, it looks like it.
给他们一点时间
Give 'em time.
我喜欢南茜
I like Nancy.
她让我想起我当年刚认识的你妈
She reminds me of your Mom when we first met.
她们长得一点也不像
They don't look anything alike.
我指的不是长相，而是…
I'm not talking about looks;I'm talking about that...
那种活力，很难形容啦
spark, that spirit,that, ah, "je ne sais quoi."
学校还好吗？
How are things at school?
你知道的
Oh, you know.
书太多，书柜不够放，屋顶漏水，预算删减
We got more books than bookcases, roof leaks, budget cutbacks...
真有点担心他们明年不会续聘我
Little worried they might not ask me back next year.
有很多老师比我经验更丰富
There's plenty of teachers with a lot more experience than me.
不管怎样，我都以你为傲
I'm proud of you regardless.
我感觉不到
Doesn't feel that way.
为什么我觉得你还是因为我而不太痛快？
Why do I feel like you're still embarrassed by me?
没关系，爸，你大可承认
And it's okay, Dad, you can admit it.
- 你又想吵架吗？
You're not trying to start something...?
- 不是…
No. No, no.
但我们终于讲话了，这样很好，那就来聊吧
But, you know, we're finally talking, and it's good, so let's talk.
我一直让你觉得丢脸
I've always been an embarrassment to you.
对不对？你以前来看我
I have, haven't l? Even when you used to come visit me,
别人盯着我看，你还是介意
you used to squirm when all those eyeballs would click my way.
你从来就无法接受
You've never been able to accept it.
你说得对
You're right.
有时候跟你在一起很难受
It is tough being with you sometimes -
我最讨厌跟你去餐厅，大家都用那种眼神看你
I hate it when we go to restaurants and people give you those looks.
有时候我…
Sometimes, I just...
我觉得好无助
I just feel so helpless.
我这辈子都在帮别人修东西
You know, I've always been a guy who could fix things...
但有样东西我一直修不好
...but the one thing I could never fix was the one thing
那就是伤你最深的东西
that was hurting you most.
这不需要修啦
It doesn't need fixing.
没人能修好
Nobody can fix it.
我知道  我知道
I know. I know.
但也许是我的错
But maybe it's my fault.
也许是我遗传给你的
Maybe I gave it to you.
这些肉应该熟了
I think these babies are done.
快点
Come on, guys.
媒体中心再过两分钟，就要关了
We only have two minutes before the media center closes.
后面的跟上来，靠旁边走
Hurry up, back there. Stay to the side, guys.
靠旁边走…我不是讲了吗？后面的快一点，跟上来
Stay to the side. What did I tell you?Guys in the back, come on, hurry up.
爸？
Dad?
你怎么会来这里？
What are you, ah,what are you doing here?
你不是说学校缺书柜吗？
You said you needed bookcases,didn't you?
你爸要帮我们的图书馆钉书柜
Your Father's built us new bookshelves for the library.
流程跑起来有点慢啦
Things are a little slow at the office.
这边请
This way, gentlemen.
我有样东西要给你
Oh, and I got you something for your collection.
科恩老师，你快戴啊
Put it on, Mr. Cohen.
硬帽子戴在顽固的脑袋上面
A hard hat for an extremely hard head.
各位同学，他是我爸爸
Hey, class, that's my dad.
- 嗨，科恩先生
Hi, Mr. Cohen!
- 嗨
Hi!
过来
Come on.
来啊
Come on!
希拉里没说是为了什么事？
And, and Hilarie didn't say what this was about?
我不知道
No idea.
我们正好下课，她说要来你的教室找你
We were at recess and she said she needs to see you in your classroom.
可能是和明年的事有关吧
I think it might have to do with next year.
他来了
Here he is.
布莱德
Brad.
请你过来一下，好吗？
Would you come over here a moment, please?
希拉里有事要宣布
Hilarie's got an announcement to make.
有些人可能注意到
Some of you may have noticed
最近几个礼拜，有个人一直在学校里旁观
an observer hanging around school the last few weeks.
他是来评估我们的一位老师
Well, he was here to assess one of our teachers.
科恩老师
Mr. Cohen.
我要宣布我们的科恩老师
And I'm here to announce that our very own Brad Cohen has been chosen
在乔治亚州的教育界，新教育工作者中脱颖而出
from amongst all the new educators in the state of
获选为本年度的最佳教师
Georgia to be Sallie Mae's First Year Teacher of the Year.
我看着我的学生们，我觉得自己也像个小孩
As I looked at my students, I felt like a kid inside.
因为小孩看待人生的观点和多数的成年人不一样
Because children look at life differently than most audits.
他们看着这个世界，会说我要做，不是我做不到，我也一样
They see the world and say, I will.Not I can't. And so did l.
这件衬衫太紧了，标签刺得我的背好痛
This shirt's too tight.The label's digging in my back...
标签我剪掉了，真搞不懂你有什么好紧张的
I cut out the label. I don't know what you're so nervous about.
你每天都在面对群众啊
You're in front of a crowd every day.
这些人可不是二年级的小孩
Well, these aren't second-graders.
现在...
Now...
天哪，真希望我可以隐形
Oh, man, I wish I was invisible.
这你就永远不必担心了
Well, that is something you'll never have to worry about.
别乱动…
Hold still, hold still!
我爱你
I love you.
科恩老师加油！
Go, Mr. Cohen!
加油，波波，你一定可以的
Come on, Bobo,you can get through this --
放心吧，他绝对没问题
Don't worry.He's going to get through it.
你们刚才听到的怪声
The noise you just heard is the Tourette Syndrome
就是我从6岁就得的图雷特氏症
I've been living with since I was six years old.
我今天站在这里，是因为有很多人的爱与支持
I'm standing up here today because the love and support of a lot of people put me up here -
我的家人
My family,
我学校的大家庭，我的学生和所有好朋友
my school family,my students, and all my friends.
这个奖要归功给他们
I owe this award to all of them.
但我也要感谢我这辈子
But I also owe it to the toughest,
最难搞、也最执着的老师
and, and most dedicated teacher I ever had:
我忠实的伙伴，图雷特氏症
my Constant Companion. My Tourette's.
你们可能会觉得不可思议，怎么会感谢一种残疾
Now, some of you may think that's pretty weird to thank a disability...
还称之为好老师？
and calling it a great teacher?
这的确很奇怪
That's really weird.
我是指，我从残疾中学到了什么呢？
I mean, what could I possibly learn from a disability?
盖伦，请说
Yes, Gaylon.
你学会了坚持到底
You learned to keep going.
伊莱？
Eli?
你学会了不让残疾阻止你
You learned to not let it stop you.
托马斯，请说
Yes, Thomas.
你学会了不被残疾打倒
You learned to not let it win!
答对了
That's right.
应对我的图雷特氏症让我学到任何人都从未学过的、最有价值的一课
Coping with my Tourette's has taught me the most valuable lesson that anyone could ever learn:
那就是千万别让任何事阻止你去追逐梦想
And that is to never let anything stop you from chasing your dream;
阻止你工作，或是寻找乐趣，或是坠入爱河
from working or playing or falling in love.
没错
That's right.
应对我的图雷特氏症让我学到了这个最宝贵的一课…
Coping with my Tourette's has taught me the most valuable lesson....
托马斯，请说
Yes, Thomas.
你礼拜一上课能不能带奖牌，去讲故事给我们听？
Can you bring that award to show and tell on Monday?
没问题
You bet.
(布莱德后来拿到了硕士学位)
(他也实现了毕生的愿望)
(扮成“荷马”亚特兰大勇士队的吉祥物)
(布莱德和南茜在2006年结婚)
(他们住在亚特兰大)
(这是真实生活中的布莱德·科恩)
(他一直做着他最喜欢的)
(教育工作)